<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Matthew</firstname>
      <surname>McNaney</surname>
    <email>matt at tux dot appstate dot edu</email>
    </author>

    <pubdate>2003-06-13</pubdate>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>

        <date>2003-06-12</date>

        <authorinitials>MM</authorinitials>

        <revremark>First release</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>User documentation for the phpWebSite Calendar module</para>
    </abstract>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Calendar</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Calendar allows you to post events on your web page. It displays
    these events in daily, weekly, and monthly views. It also includes a small
    view which allows users to see what is coming up within the next few days.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>You can get to the administrative functions of Calendar two ways.
    The first way is to view an event, month, week, day, or year. As soon as
    you access the Calendar module, the administrative panel will appear at
    the top of the page. The other way to access calendar is by clicking on
    the Calendar icon in the Control Panel. Calendar&#39;s function is to post
    events. To get started, we will create an event.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Creating Events</title>

    <para>Click on the <emphasis role="bold">Create New Event</emphasis> in
    the Calendar administration panel. You will come to the event form. Here
    is what you will need to fill out.<itemizedlist spacing="normal"><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Active</emphasis> - This defaults to &#39;On&#39;. If you want
    the event to be hidden from user view until later, change this to
    &#39;Off&#39;.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Title</emphasis>
    - Pretty self-explanatory. This is the title of the event. Keep it short
    and don&#39;t include the date or time. Let the rest of the form handle
    that.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis>
    - Although not required, you should fill this in with a description of the
    event and its importance.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Image</emphasis> - You can upload an image to be associated
    with your event. Just click the Browse button and choose an image from
    your hard drive. You can also use an image that is already on the server
    by picking it from the drop down menu. Set your selection to
    &#60;None&#62; if you decide you don&#39;t want an image with your event.
    Finally, select an image and click the Remove Button to delete the image
    file from the server.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Template</emphasis> - The template controls the layout of your
    event when it is viewed. Normally, the default.tpl template is sufficient.
    If however, there is another template file you wish to use, select it from
    the drop down menu.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Event
    Type</emphasis> - There are four event types. Click the radio buttonnext
    to the one you wish to use.<orderedlist><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Interval</emphasis> - This event has a definite start and end
    time and date.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Starts
    At</emphasis> - This event has a definite start time but an undetermined
    end time.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Deadline</emphasis>
    - The start time of this event is irrelevant but the end time is vital.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">All Day</emphasis> - This event doesn&#39;t have a start or
    end time (e.g. a holiday).</para></listitem></orderedlist></para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Start Time</emphasis> - This is the time the event starts. You
    do not need to set this for the All Day or Deadline event type.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">End Time</emphasis> - This is the time the event ends. You
    should set this for Interval and Deadline events, but not for Starts At or
    All Day events.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Start
    Date</emphasis> - The date the event starts. Note that the Start Date must
    always be before the End Date.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">End Date</emphasis> - The date the event ends. Normally this
    is the same day as the Start Date, however you can create an Interval
    event that takes place over several days.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
    role="bold">Categories</emphasis> - If you have created categories in
    FatCat, you can associate the event to one or more of them. If your event
    is important, consider clicking the Sticky check box. This will assure it
    is seen in the What&#39;s Related box.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></para>

    <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Create Event</emphasis> button once
    you have finished filling out the form. If there aren&#39;t any errors,
    your event should now appear on the calendar.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Editing Events</title>

    <para>To change an event&#39;s data, find it using the calendar and view
    it. As an administrator, you should see an <emphasis role="bold">Edit</emphasis>
    link. Click on that link to go to the edit form. Your changes will not be
    saved until you click the <emphasis role="bold">Update Event</emphasis>
    button.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Deleting Events</title>

    <para>To remove an event, click on the <emphasis role="bold">Delete</emphasis>
    link that will appear when you are viewing an event. This will permanently
    remove the event and its repeats from the system, so be careful.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Repeating Events</title>

    <para>If your event needs to post more than once, you should repeat the
    event. Below the event form is the repeat form. To get started, click the
    check box next to <emphasis role="bold">Repeat Event until</emphasis> and
    pick the termination date. The repeats will cease after this date.</para>

    <para>Now click on the radio button next to your repeat option.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Daily</emphasis> - The event will appear
        everyday until the termination date.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis><emphasis role="bold">Weekly</emphasis></emphasis> -
        The event will appear on every checked weekday.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Monthly</emphasis> - Choose whether you
        want the event to appear at the beginning of every month, the end of
        every month, or every month on the same day as the start date.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Yearly</emphasis> - Choose this if you
        want the event to appear on the same day every year.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Every</emphasis> - Here you can choose
        specific weekday of each month for your event to appear. For example,
        you could choose to have an event repeat on the second Tuesday of
        every month. First pick which week you want the event to appear in.
        Then choose the weekday. Finally, choose a specific month or the
        &#34;Every Month&#34; option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>When you are finished setting your repeat options, click either the
    Create Event button (if you are making a new event) or the Update Event
    button (if you are editing an old one).</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Settings</title>

    <para>Clicking on the <emphasis role="bold">Settings</emphasis> link will
    take you to the page of the same name. There are only a few settings you
    may want to alter and you shouldn&#39;t have to do so often.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Mini Month</emphasis> - uncheck this if
        you do not want the small month view to show in the user view.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Days Ahead</emphasis> - Set the amount of
        days in the future you want the calendar to look ahead for events. Set
        it to zero if you do not want it to display at all.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Cache Calendar Views</emphasis> - Check
        this box if you want the calendar to cache some of its pages. This can
        increase the speed of some views (especially month and year).</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">User Submitted Events</emphasis> - Check
        this box if you want to allow users to submit events.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Reindex FatCat</emphasis> - If you have
        deleted an event and it is still showing up in What&#39;s Related,
        check this box.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Click the Submit button when finished.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Refresh</title>

    <para>If you are caching the calendar views, changes made to the events
    may not appear immediately. If you are impatient, click the <emphasis
    role="bold">Refresh</emphasis> link on the calendar panel to clear the
    cache.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>User Submitted Events</title>

    <para>If you are allowing user submitted events (see Settings) then users
    will be able to suggest events. They will not be able to post repeats
    (imagine an event repeated daily from 2003 to 2009) so they will need to
    put that information in the description. To approve the event, go to the
    Approval module.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <para>Once you create your first event, using calendar should be pretty
    clear. If you have any problems, please visit us at Sourceforge. If you
    have any questions or comments about this document, please email me at:
    matt at tux dot appstate dot edu</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
