<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Darren</firstname>
      <surname>Greene</surname>
      <email>dg49379 at tux dot appstate dot edu</email>
    </author>

    <pubdate>2003-06-19</pubdate>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
        <date>2003-06-19</date>
        <authorinitials>DG</authorinitials>
        <revremark>First release</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>User documentation for the phpWebSite FAQ module</para>
    </abstract>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>FAQ (Frequently Asked Questions)</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>
    The FAQ module provides an interface to view frequently asked
    questions and answers.  The questions that are answered over and over
    via phone, email, etc. are ideal questions to be managed by the FAQ module. 
 
    The FAQ module uses an algorithm for sorting and listing FAQs.
    The equation takes into consideration how many times a FAQ has been accessed, how long it
    has been since it was last viewed, and the average rating given by
    users.  The rating and sorting methods were designed to force the FAQs that are
    accessed the most often and have the highest score rating to appear
    toward the top of a users search results. 
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>
    To begin adding FAQs, log in as an administrator with the
    permission to add new FAQs activated.  If you do not login with the proper
    permission enabled, then any FAQs added will be considered  
    suggestions, which then must be approved by an administrator.  If you
    have just installed the FAQ module, then you must access FAQ by going
    to the <emphasis>Control Panel -> Site Content ->
    FAQ</emphasis>.  Since you are logged in as an administrator, FAQ
    provides you with several more advanced menu options than a regular
    user, such as access to statistics about your collection of FAQs,
    ability to list unapproved and hidden FAQs, and a settings link to
    define how the FAQ module will organize and present the FAQs to users.  Click the link
    that says <emphasis>'New'</emphasis> to start adding new FAQs.  The <emphasis>'View'</emphasis> link will
    show all the FAQs you have inserted. 
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Viewing FAQs</title>

    <para>
    To view the FAQs that have been inserted into the FAQ module and are
    viewable (in other words not hidden or unapproved), click
    <emphasis>'View'</emphasis> from the FAQ menu.  The
    arrangement and organization of the listed FAQs depends on which
    layout mode is selected from the <emphasis>'Settings'</emphasis> option of the FAQ administrative
    panel.  There are four possible layout modes that represent the
    typical ways that users expect the format for a listing of FAQs to
    be presented. 
    </para> 
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Adding FAQs</title>

    <para>
    To add a new FAQ to the FAQ module, login as an administrator with the
    permission to add a new FAQ and click the <emphasis>'New'</emphasis> link from
    the FAQ administrative menu to access a form to submit a new FAQ.
    The different fields are explained below:  

    <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Question</emphasis> - This is the
      frequently asked question.  It is a required field.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Answer</emphasis> - The answer
      to your question.  This field is required.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Category</emphasis> - This field
      will only display if the FatCat module is installed.  The category
      chosen will be used in the category layout mode to group FAQs.  The
      FAQs in the same category are also used by any module of phpWebSite
      that utilizes the FatCat <emphasis>What's Related</emphasis>
      feature.  The category field is also required if there are any
      categories defined within FatCat.
      </para>
     </listitem> 

    </itemizedlist> 

   </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>FAQ view mode</title>

    <para>
    The FAQ view mode which is referenced several times in this chapter
    refers to the view that has a single FAQ followed by it's answer.
    The hit counter for FAQs is also updated from this view.  There are several elements that may appear in view
    mode and are explained below:
    <itemizedlist>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">What's Related</emphasis> - If Fatcat is
      installed and you have been assigning FAQs to particular
      categories then a "What's Related" box will appear on the screen
      that lists other FAQs in the same category.
      </para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Comments</emphasis> - If the FAQ setting
      to allow users to post comments is enabled, then any user comments
      on the current FAQ being viewed will appear on this page.
      </para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Admin Menu</emphasis> - If you are logged
      in as an administrator with any of the permissions enabled to
      edit, hide, show, approve, unapprove, or delete FAQs, then the Admin Menu box
      will be shown, giving you quick access to administer a FAQ.
      </para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Change Score Rating For This
      FAQ</emphasis> - This box will show up if you have the admin
      permission to change the ratings of FAQs.  The hits and the
      average score rating are both editable and both of these values
      are combined to give a new composite score.  An example of when
      you might want to change or reset the score rating of a FAQ is
      after changing the question or providing a better answer.
      </para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
   </para>

  <note>
   <para>
    To get to the view mode under certain layout views of FAQ you
    must click the <emphasis>'feedback'</emphasis> link.  The
    <emphasis>'feedback'</emphasis> will only appear if the FAQ
    settings to allow users to rate FAQs is checked.  
   </para>
  </note>

  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Submission and Administering Suggested FAQs</title>

    <para>
    If a user is not logged in or is logged in as an administrator that
    lacks the permission to add new FAQs, then the FAQ module will only
    allow users to suggest FAQs.  On the FAQ menu the menu option for
    <emphasis>'New'</emphasis> will instead say <emphasis>'Suggest a
    FAQ'</emphasis>.  Any suggested FAQs will not be active
    or show when viewing the current FAQs, because they must
    first be approved by an administrator.  Suggested FAQs may lack an
    answer when initially submitted, but before being allowed to be
    approved an answer must be provided.  The form for suggesting a FAQ
    has two extra optional fields for the user's name and email address.
    This contact information is to allow administrators the ability to
    contact the sender if there is a question about the FAQ the user
    has submitted.  To view and approve suggested FAQs follow these steps: 

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Login as an administrator of FAQ and click 'Unapproved /
        Hidden' from the FAQ administrative menu.
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>
        If there are no FAQs that need to be approved, then the list will of course
        be empty.  But, we will assume there is at least one FAQ that
        needs to be approved.  So, select the a FAQ from the list that you would like to
        administer.
        </para> 
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>
        You have several different choices from the drop down menu:

        <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
          <listitem>
           <para>
           <emphasis role="bold">View</emphasis> - The
           <emphasis>'View'</emphasis> option will take you to a screen showing what the FAQ will look like
           if it is approved.  This option is important if there is any ambiguity about the question the user has
           submitted, since you will be able to see if the user
           provided their email address.  If so, you can
           click the option to <emphasis>'Send Email'</emphasis> to use the built in mail interface of
           FAQ to send the user who suggested the FAQ an email asking
           them to clarify their question.  
           </para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
           <para> 
           <emphasis role="bold">Edit</emphasis> - This is probably the most
           typical option to choose, since you will probably need to redefine the question
           submitted and provide an acceptable answer.  So, make any changes in
           <emphasis>'Edit'</emphasis> and after saving the changes you will be brought back to the unapproved
           listing.
           </para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
           <para>
           <emphasis role="bold">Approve</emphasis> - Choose this option to go
           ahead and approve the FAQ, which will make the FAQ active and viewable,
           providing that you have not chosen to hide the FAQ.  The FAQ must
           have an answer before it is allowed to be approved.  There is also an approve
           option in the <emphasis>'View mode'</emphasis> of any FAQ.
           </para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
           <para>
           <emphasis role="bold">Delete</emphasis> - If you do not like the question
           submitted, then choose this option to delete the FAQ.  
           </para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
           <para>
           <emphasis role="bold">Hide and Show</emphasis> - These
           options are of little significance in the unapproved list
           since by the FAQ being unapproved it is already not viewable
           by users.  
           </para> 
          </listitem>

        </itemizedlist>

       </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>
        If you chose a path other than to hide or delete the unapproved FAQ
        then the FAQ should now be approved and viewable.
        </para>
      </listitem>

      </orderedlist>
    </para>

    <note>
     <para>
     When a FAQ is suggested it is also registered with the Approval module
     and can be approved or deleted using the Approval module's interface.
     </para>
    </note>

  </section>
  
  <section>
   <title>Hiding, Showing and Deleting Current FAQs</title>
   
   <para>
   There are several different methods to administer existing FAQs.  

   <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
    <listitem>
     <para>
     The easiest and probably the most convenient way is to login as an
     administrator and access the FAQ in <emphasis>'view mode'</emphasis>.  You can tell if
     you are in <emphasis>view mode</emphasis> by seeing the option to rate the FAQ.  If you are using
     either the bookmarked or question and answer layout modes then you
     will need the ability for users to rate FAQs enabled under
     settings to be able to directly administer FAQs in <emphasis>'view mode'</emphasis>.  Once you are viewing a FAQ, then
     an administrative menu will appear below the question and
     answer with the options that you have permission to use 
     such as hide, show, approve, unapprove, and delete.
     </para>
   </listitem>

   <listitem>
    <para>
    The other method is to use the special queries by clicking on <emphasis>'Stats'</emphasis>
    from the FAQ administrative menu.  All of the
    different queries have the same interface, so use whichever query
    that will allow you to find the FAQ you are interested in faster.  To guarantee that the
    FAQ you wish to change is shown, you should choose the option to <emphasis>'Show
    All FAQs'</emphasis>.  Select the FAQ from the listing and
    choose from the drop down menu the option that you wish to perform on
    the FAQ (only the options that you have permission to use will be shown).
    </para>
   </listitem>

   </itemizedlist>

  </para> 
  </section>   

  <section>
   <title>Statistics</title>

   <para>
   To access the statistics section of FAQ click the link for <emphasis>'Stats'</emphasis>
   from the FAQ administrative menu.  The top of this section gives a
   quick overview of all the FAQs added to the FAQ module.  This shows
   the total counts of the number of FAQs that are current viewable, hidden, and
   unapproved.  Also, in the 'Stats' section there are several different
   query options to list FAQs that meet a certain criteria, these queries are
   explained below:

    <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Faqs with no activity in the last X
      months.</emphasis> - Activity in this case can mean several different
      things such as a user has viewed the FAQ, the FAQ has been rated, or
      has been changed by an administer.  If any FAQs have not had any
      activity in the number of months chosen for the query, then they will
      be listed.
      </para>
     </listitem>
     
     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">FAQs with a high number of hits and a low score
      rating.</emphasis> - This query doesn't use any type of set constant
      to determine the FAQs that are considered to have a high number of
      hits or a low score rating, but instead uses the number of hits and
      ratings of all the FAQs in the database to determine which FAQs meet the
      criteria specified.  This particular query will show a listing of FAQs that have been viewed
      by many users, but the users have either not scored the FAQ or
      have consistently given it a low score.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">FAQs with a low number of hits and high score
      rating.</emphasis> - This query doesn't use any type of set constant
      to determine the FAQs that are considered to have a low number of
      hits or a high score, but instead uses the number of hits and
      rating of all FAQs in the database to determine which FAQs fall within this category.
      This particular query will show a listing of FAQs that have not been
      viewed by many users, but the users who have viewed the FAQ have rated
      the FAQ very positively.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">FAQs that do not have a category
      selected.</emphasis> - If you have inserted FAQs into the FAQ module
      before the FatCat(phpWebSite Category module) was installed, then any FAQs
      inserted will not have a category.  This will not be a problem
      unless you select to use the Category layout mode, because any FAQs
      that lack a category will not show up.  This query helps
      administrators quickly determine which FAQs do not have a category, so
      that they can choose a proper category.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Show all FAQs in database.</emphasis> - Use this
      query if you wish to show all FAQs in the database whether they are visible or
      not. Ideal for general administration of FAQs.
      </para>
     </listitem>
 
     </itemizedlist>  

   </para>
   </section>

   <section>
    <title>FAQ Settings</title>
  
     <section>
      <title>Options</title>

      <para>
       <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
        <listitem>
         <para>
         <emphasis role="bold">Allow users to rate FAQs.</emphasis> - Toggles
         whether or not users are allowed to rate a FAQ by giving it a rating
         of one through five, with five meaning the FAQ was considered excellent.  Under certain layout
         modes if this option is unchecked then the 'feedback' option
         associated with each FAQ will not appear, since the
         feedback link is meant to allow users the ability to rate a FAQ.
         </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
         <para>
         <emphasis role="bold">Allow users to post comments.</emphasis> - If
         you do not have the comment module installed, then this option will not
         appear under settings.  If this option is selected, then each FAQ is
         allowed to have comments posted by users and they will appear at the
         bottom of the FAQs in <emphasis>'view mode'</emphasis>.
         </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
         <para>
         <emphasis role="bold">Allow users to suggest FAQs.</emphasis> -
         Toggles the option of whether users who are not logged in as an
         administrator with the permission to add a FAQ are allowed to suggest
         a FAQ for approval.  If this option is unselected, then users will be
         presented with the list of FAQs without a menu at the top, since the
         only option would be to 'View' the FAQs.
         </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
         <para>
         <emphasis role="bold">Add a menu link for the FAQ module.</emphasis> -
         Click this hypertext to create a link on one of your navigation menus
         so that users can view the FAQs without being logged in or have to go
         through the control panel to access the FAQ module.  Follow the instructions after clicking the
         link to add a menu link, and after the new link is added you
         will be returned back to the FAQ settings section.
         </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
     </para>
    </section>

   <section>
     <title>Layout View</title>

     <para>The different layouts allow you pick from several different
     common views that are typical of how users expect FAQs to be
     displayed.  Plus, some of the layouts are more convenient depending
     on how many FAQs you need to show.  For example, if you have a large number of FAQs, then it would probably be best
     to use the category layout, so that your FAQs will be grouped into categories.  There are
     several help system icons that will help you choose a layout.
     The help blocks give both a description and a simple example.

     <itemizedlist>
     <listitem>

     <para>
     <emphasis role="bold">Basic Question and Answer
     View</emphasis> - This layout doesn't use categories to group FAQs, but instead features the
     FAQs by simply listing them in the manner chosen by showing the
     question and answer on the same page.  The FAQs are
     sorted by their composite score, which consists of the number of times
     they have been accessed, their score rating, and the last time the
     FAQ was viewed. 

      <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
       <para>
       <emphasis role="bold">Limit results by showing X question per
       page.</emphasis> - For the value X, put in the number of FAQs that you
       would like to show at one time on a page.  If there are more
       FAQs than can fit on a page using the number you specified, then at the bottom of
       the page listing the FAQs, there will be a navigation panel allowing users to
       page through the FAQs.
       </para>
      </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Bookmarked Questions</emphasis> - Under this
      layout the FAQ questions will be shown at the top of the page and will
      be linked to the question and answer, lower on the page, along with links
      back up to the top of page.  The number of FAQs that appear on a page
      is governed by the number specified for limiting the results on a
      page under this section of the settings.  If you have enabled the ability for users to rate the FAQs, then
      a 'feedback' option will be provided for each FAQ.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     <listitem>
      <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Question and Answer</emphasis> - This layout
      will show each FAQ by listing the question followed by the answer.  The number of FAQs that appear on a page
      is governed by the number specified for limiting the results on a
      page, which can be adjusted from the settings section of FAQ.
      If you have enabled the ability for users to rate the FAQs, then 
      a 'feedback' option will be provided for each FAQ.
      </para>
     </listitem>

     </itemizedlist>

    </para></listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>
     <emphasis role="bold">No Categories - Hyperlinked Questions</emphasis> - As
     the name suggests this layout will simple list all the questions
     in one list and then users have to click on a question to view the
     question and answer.  The number of FAQs shown on a page is
     controlled by the user.
     </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>
     <emphasis role="bold">Category View</emphasis> - The
     category layout relies on the FatCat module to group the FAQs and
     this layout will not appear if FatCat is not installed.  The
     categories must be created using the FatCat module.  If a
     category has any FAQs in it, then after a user clicks <emphasis>'View'</emphasis> from
     the FAQ menu then that category will show along with the number of FAQs in the
     category and the category description (if there is one).  Any
     subcategories will be shown below the parent category and will be
     indented.  If a parent category doesn't have any FAQs in it, but it's
     children does have FAQs, then the parent category title will still
     be displayed , but it will not be a link.  Users can click a 
     category name to see a list of all FAQs in the category chosen, along with
     link back to the list of categories and if applicable links to
     the subcategories and parent categories.  To view the answer to a
     FAQ question, the user must then click on one of the questions.  
     </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    </para>
   </section>
   
   <section>
    <title>Legend for Rating FAQs</title>
    
    <para>
    If you would like to change the text that users associate
    with a particular score for a FAQ, then you can edit the text using
    this section.  The FAQ module is designed to work with five as
    being the user's opinion for saying that the FAQ was excellent and
    with one being the FAQ was of no use at all.  This text appears in
    the drop down menu beside the question that says <emphasis>How would you
    rate this FAQ</emphasis> when viewing a FAQ. 
    </para>
   </section>

  </section> 

  <section>
   <title>Tips for Administrators of FAQ</title>

   <para>
   If you have FatCat installed then it is suggested that you adjust the constant titled
   FATCAT_LINK_CUTOFF in mod/fatcat/conf/config.php file to the number of
   characters that you want to chop off your questions to store in
   fatcat.  You don't want this cutoff small, since the questions will
   appear in the 'whats related' box as incomprehensible.  In other
   words, you don't want to have questions that show up as 'What about...'.
   </para>

   <para>
    Suggested layout changes that require the use of the Layout Manager
    <itemizedlist spacing="normal">
     <listitem>
     <para>
     The user comments which will display when a FAQ is viewed would 
     probably look best if set to show at the bottom of the page.
     </para>
     </listitem>
  
     <listitem>
     <para>
     The Menuman box to add a new menulink, which will display in the
     Settings  section after clicking 'Add menu link for the FAQ module'
     would also look better if moved to the bottom of the page.
     </para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

   </para>
  </section>

</chapter>