<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Steven</firstname>
      <surname>Levin</surname>
      <email>steven at tux dot appstate dot edu</email>
    </author>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Menu Manager</title>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>Menus within phpWebSite are used for site navigation. To begin using
    the Menu Manager module you must go to the adminisrative side. The menu
    manager can be found under the Site Content tab of your controlpanel. The
    link says Menu Manager and may have an icon that looks like an open menu.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click on the textual link or the icon to continue.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Listing Menus</title>

    <para>When you first startup the module what you see is the Menu Manger
    admin menu followed by a list of menus if there are any in the database.
    If there are no menus you should see a message that says: There are no
    menus in the database at this time. The admin menu at the top allows you
    to list menus (2), create menus (3), and go to the image manager (4). This
    menu will follow you around and be available on most of the administrative
    screens. At any point you can click the List Menus link and get back to
    this page. Each menu in the list can be edited, deleted, and (activated /
    deactivated).</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Clicking the edit button on the row of the menu you wish to edit
        will take you to section (5) of this chapter which will be discussed
        later.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Clicking the delete button on the row of the menu you wish to
        delete will take you to a Yes/No confirmation. The confirmation is to
        make sure you want to delete the menu (make sure this is what you want
        to do and that you have selected the correct menu). Click Yes to
        remove the menu and all of its links from the database. Click No to
        cancel the deletion process.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Clicking the Activate/Deactivate button on the row of the menu
        you wish to change will toggle it between being viewable by the public
        and not.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Creating New Menus</title>

    <para>The menu creation page allows you to configure all of the settings
    for your new menu. The options you see here can be changed later via the
    menu settings when you are editing your menu. Settings for the most part
    can be left at their default values and the menu will function the way
    most expect. Most of the options are for those who would like to really
    configure their menu.</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click on the Create Menu link in the admin menu at the top of
        the page, this will take you to the menu creation page.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Next begin to fill out the fields appropriately.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Menu Title: The text title that will show up at the top of the
        menu. You should always provide a title for your menu, altough it is
        not a required field, so you can distinguish it from other menus.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Menu Spacer: This value is a numeric value which represents the
        number of extra spaces the menu will add automatically to each nested
        level of the menu. The menu will always start with 0 space at the
        first level of the menu. (ie. a value of 2 for the menu spacer will
        put 2 spaces on the first nest of the menu and 4 spaces for the second
        nest)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Template: The template for the menu is just there to give the
        ability for someone to highly configure their menu. For most this
        option will just stay at default unless you really know what you are
        doing.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>If you would like more information on templating please see
            the TEMPLATE.txt doc in the docs directory for the Menu Manager.
            The image map checkbox is there for furthur templating
            configuration.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Allow View: The allow view option allows you to choose which
        modules must be active in order for the menu appear. You can select
        one module or multiple modules. The default is to select all of the
        modules so if none are selected then the menu will be visable for all
        of the modules currently installed. If a module is installed after the
        menu is created, and you want the menu to show up for the module, you
        will have to come and select it under the menu settings.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Default Theme Variable: This allows you to choose where the menu
        will defaultly show up on the page after it is created. This is the
        only time you can set this option within the menu manager. After it is
        set it can be changed via the layout modules box move option. The
        values for this option are pretty self-explanitory, it will show up
        exactly where it says.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Menu Indent: The menu indent can be one of two things a
        character or an image. If the radio button is selected for a character
        then the menu manager will use the character selected from the
        dropdown box before every link in the menu. Also if an activity color
        is set for that character then the character will turn that color when
        the link it shows up before is the link that was just clicked. If the
        radio button is selected for an image then the images choosen will
        show up before each link. Depending on the activity of the link. The
        images found in the dropbox here can be uploaded via the image
        manager.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Image Manager</title>

    <para>The image manager just gives you a web-based interface to upload
    images you want to use as an indent item at that is all. If you do not
    plan on using an image for your indent item then you will not need to use
    the image manager. Current images can also be removed from the system via
    this page by just selecting the image and clicking delete.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Editing Menus</title>

    <para>To edit a menu you must list all of the current menus as described
    before and click the edit button next to the menu you are wanting to edit.
    Now you will see a list of all the current links in the menu, if there are
    no links in the menu you will get a message that says: No items for this
    menu.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Adding Menu Items</title>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A menu item may be added to the menu by clicking on the Add
          Menu Item button at the bottom of the page.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>After you click this you will see a screen which will give you
          three options.</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Title: The text representation of the link that will be
              placed in the menu. This field is required.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>URL: The url of the link you are wanting to add. If
              pagemaster pages are available they will show up here in a
              dropdown box to be selected. You can either fill out the url or
              pick a pagemaster page. When a pagemaster page is chosen then
              the url field is populating accordingly so it does not need to
              be filled out. In this case the user submitted url will be
              ignored.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Display: This option allows you define how the link will
              act and display on your site.</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Internal: The page is internal to the site and the
                  menu will expand at that point where the menu is clicked.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>External: The page is external which means it is not
                  located within your site (ie. links to another site) this
                  will not detect your position in the menu.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>New Window: This option will cause the link to open in
                  a new browser window.</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Now select where on the menu you would like the menu item to
          go. The very top radiobutton means you want the link to be a top
          level link (ie. not nested under another link). If any other
          radiobutton listed next to another menu item is selected that means
          you want the link you are adding to be nested under the item
          selected. Finally if this is the first link you are adding to the
          menu then it can only be a top-level link.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Basic Edit</title>

      <para>This is the first mode you will see when editing your menu. At any
      time you can switch to the advanced edit mode (5.3) by clicking the Turn
      On Advanced Edit button. The basic edit allows you to edit the textual
      representation of the menu item, change the activity of the menu item,
      change the order of the menu item, and delete menu items. All of the
      edit and delete options can be done in mass by checking more than one
      check box and then clicking the appropriate submit button. Ordering of
      menu items can only be done one at a time by clicking the arrow in the
      direction you want it to go. To update the menu item:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>To update the text, change the value in the textfield of the
          link you want to edit and check the box next to the link, now click
          the Update Menu Items button and you are done.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To toggle the activity of a menu item check the box next to
          the item you want to change and then click the Activate/Deactivate
          button.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To change the order of a menu item just click the up or down
          link next to the item you want to move. Only items that are on the
          same level (in the same nest) can be order. An item can not be moved
          to another nest at this point in time. This option is in the plan
          for future versions.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To delete an item check the box next to it and then click the
          delete button. A confirmation will then appear making sure you are
          deleting the links you want. If you click yes that link will be
          deleted along with ALL of the links nested under it.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title> Advanced Edit</title>

      <para>The advanced edit mode will also allow you to edit the textual
      representation of a menu item and delete a menu item. It will also allow
      you to edit the url for the menu item, and the display method as
      described earlier. All of the edit and delete options can be done in
      mass by checking more than one check box and then clicking the
      appropriate submit button. To update the menu item:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Edit the textfield containing the information you want to
          change.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Then check the box next to the item and click the Update Menu
          Items button.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>If you select a pagemaster page then you do not need to edit
          the url field, the menu will take care of that for you.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To update the display select the display you want then check
          the box next to the item and click the Update Menu Items button.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To delete an item check the box next to it and then click the
          delete button. A confirmation will then appear making sure you are
          deleting the links you want. If you click yes that link will be
          deleted along with ALL of the links nested under it.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Settings</title>

      <para>The settings button will take you to the settings for your menu.
      These are all the same options seen before when creating a menu. Click
      save at the bottom to update any changes you may make on this page.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Add Module Default</title>

      <para>The ability to add module defaults allows you to add a link of a
      specific module&#39;s user side to the menu. After clicking this button,
      then select the module you want to add a link for and then select the
      position you would like to see the link in the menu. Finally click Add
      Menu Item. Your are done.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>