<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo><author><firstname>Adam</firstname><surname>Morton</surname>
  <email>adam@NOSPAM.tux.appstate.edu</email>
  </author></chapterinfo>

  <title>PageMaster</title>

  <section><title>Introduction</title><para>The PageMaster module is used to
  create and edit web pages for your site. PageMaster also allows you to post
  a page you created as the &#34;main page&#34; for your site. It is also
  integrated into several other phpWebSite modules which extend it&#39;s
  functionality. You must have these other modules installed before the
  functionality will be available. Some of these modules and their
  functionality is as follows:</para><para><phrase role="strong">Menuman</phrase>-
  offers a quick, easy method of adding pages to your sites menus. </para><para><phrase
  role="strong">FatCat</phrase>- allows categorization of pages so users can
  easily find pages that contain related information and other items that
  contain related information.</para><para><phrase role="strong">Comments</phrase>-
  allows visitors to your site the ability to post their comments on
  information contained in your pages.</para><para>The content of a page is
  broken into two parts, a page title and page sections. Each section is
  broken into three parts, a section title, section text (the main information
  for that section), and a section image. It&#39;s good to have in mind the
  number of sections you will be using, the relative content for each section,
  and the order of these sections in your page. The section image is always
  optional. The layout of a page is dependent upon the template selected for
  that page and the layout or template of each section.</para></section>

  <section><title>Creating a Page</title><para>It is recommended that before
  you create a page using PageMaster that you plan ahead on the content and
  layout of that page before attempting to dive in and create it.Once you have
  a page planned out follow these steps to create your page:</para><orderedlist
  numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Open your <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>
  and navigate to the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis> tab.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Select the <emphasis>PageMaster</emphasis> module from the list of
  modules.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Select <emphasis>New Page</emphasis> from the
  main menu.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Enter your <emphasis>page title</emphasis>.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>If your page fits into one of your site&#39;s
  <emphasis>categories</emphasis>, select it from the list provided.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Select a <emphasis>template</emphasis> for your page. The default
  template is the only template to ship with phpWebSite.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>If you have the <emphasis>comments</emphasis> module installed,
  you can choose to allow comments on your page and whether or not to allow
  anonymous users to post comments.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Check the information
  you entered to make sure it is correct and click the <emphasis>Go</emphasis>
  button.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>You can now start adding sections to your page.
  Sections are added from top to bottom.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Enter a
  <emphasis>subtitle</emphasis> for your section.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Enter the <emphasis>body text</emphasis> for your section.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Optionally, <emphasis>select an image</emphasis> from your hard
  drive to upload to your section. If you supply an image, you must also
  supply a <emphasis>short description</emphasis> for that image in the Short
  Image Description field.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Select a <emphasis>template</emphasis>
  to use for the layout of your section.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>Check to be sure
  the information you entered is correct and click the <emphasis>Save Section</emphasis>
  button to save your section.</para></listitem> <listitem><para>You will now see the
  section you just created at the top of your page. You can choose to edit or
  delete a section by clicking the <emphasis>Edit</emphasis> or
  <emphasis>Remove</emphasis> buttons respectively within the section.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Repeat steps 10 - 14 to add more sections to your page.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>When you have added and saved all your sections, click the
  <emphasis>SAVE PAGE</emphasis> button to save your page. Be sure to
  carefully read the warning before saving the page.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>You will now be taken back to your list of pages and your new page
  will be shown in the list.</para></listitem></orderedlist><para>By default when a
  page is first saved, it is marked as hidden. To make your page viewable by
  your site visitors click the Show button for the respective page.
  Alternately you can click the Hide button to hide a page from your visitors.
  To make changes to an existing page, click the Edit button for the
  respective page. To remove an existing page, click the Delete button for the
  respective page. You will be prompted to confirm the deletion of the page
  before it is fully removed.</para></section>

  <section role="unnumbered"><title>Editing a Page</title><para>To edit a
  page, select List Pages from the Main Menu and find the page you wish to
  edit in the list of pages shown. Click the Edit button under the Action
  column for the page you wish to edit. You will be taken to the same edit
  mode as when creating a page. From here you can choose to edit or remove any
  section within the page by clicking the Editor Remove button respectively
  within the section.</para><para>To edit the page title, categories,or
  template, click the edit button located in the title bar of your page.When
  you have updated the information, click the Go button to return to editing
  the sections within your page. When all the information within your pages
  and sections are updated, click the SAVE PAGE button at the bottom of the
  page. Make sure to carefully read the warning before saving the page.</para></section>

  <section><title>Removing a Page</title><para>To remove an existing page from
  your site, select List Pages from the Main Menu and find the page you wish
  to remove. Click the Delete button under the Actions column for the
  respective page. You will be asked to confirm the deletion. If you are sure
  you want to completely remove the page, click the Yes button and the page
  will be removed. If you are not sure, click the No button and the page will
  remain. If you do not wish to delete a page but want to hide it from your
  visitor&#39;s view, you can choose to just hide it instead of fully removing
  it. Select List Pages from the Main Menu, find the page you wish to hide and
  click the Hide button for the respective page. The Hide button will turn
  into a Show button. When you are ready to show the page to the public again,
  click the Show button for that page.</para></section>

  <section><title>Setting the Main Page</title><para>To set a PageMaster page
  as your main page,select Set Main Page from the main menu. The current saved
  pages are shown with Select buttons to the right of the titles. Find the
  page you wish to have as your main page and click the respective Select
  button to set it. The current main page is marked with CURRENT in green to
  the right of the title. This also appears in the regular page list. If you
  wish to hide the main page all together, select List Pages from the Main
  Menu and click the Hide button for the respective page.</para></section>
</chapter>
