<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo><author><firstname>Adam</firstname><surname>Morton</surname>
  <email>adam@NOSPAM.tux.appstate.edu</email>
  </author></chapterinfo>

  <title>File Manager</title>

  <section><title>Introduction</title><para>The File Manager is a simple
  module that allows users to upload files to their phpWebSite sites. These
  files can be anything from mp3s to archives of data. All files should be
  categorized via the FatCat categorizer to allow them to show up in key areas
  of your site. The File Manager</para></section>

  <section><title>Adding a New File</title><para>Before uploading a new file,
  make sure you have decided what the description of the file will be and
  which of your site&#39;s categories the file will fall into. Then, follow
  these steps to upload your new file:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged in and have permission to use the File Manager.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Open
  your Control Panel.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the Site Content
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the File Manager
  module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click Add New File.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  the Browse button under Upload File and select the file you wish to upload.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill
  out the description for your file.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select
  the category or categories this file will belong to.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Submit.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Your file will be saved and you
  will be presented with the details of the uploaded file.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Return to Main to return to the current file listing.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Editing an Existing File</title><para>Before editing a file,
  make sure you have decided what changes will be made including the
  description of the file will be and which of your site&#39;s categories the
  file will fall into. You can also upload a new file to replace the current
  one. If this is the case, then have in mind where the file is located. Then,
  follow these steps to edit your file:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged in and have permission to use the File Manager.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Open
  your Control Panel.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the Site Content
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the File Manager
  module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find the file you wish to edit in
  the file listing.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the check box next
  to the file you wish to edit.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the
  Edit option from the drop down list of actions.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Go.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to change or update the
  current file with a new copy, click the Browse button under Upload File and
  select the file you wish to upload. Once you finish editing, the current
  file will be replaced by the new one you just selected.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  you wish to change or update the description, simply update the text in the
  Description box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to change the
  categories your file appears in, select those categories in the Categories
  box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Check over your changes one last time
  to make sure you haven&#39;t made any mistakes.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Submit.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Your changes will be saved and you
  will be presented with the details of the changes.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Return to Main to return to the current file listing.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Removing an Existing File</title><para>Before removing a
  file, make sure you are positive you want to remove it from the File
  Manager. Once the file is removed, it cannot be recovered. If you are sure,
  follow these steps to remove your file:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged in and have permission to use the File Manager.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Open
  your Control Panel.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the Site Content
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the File Manager
  module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find the file you wish to remove in
  the file listing.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the check box next
  to the file you wish to remove.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the
  Delete option from the drop down list of actions.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Go.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You will be asked to confirm the
  deletion of the file. If you are sure click Yes, otherwise click No.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  you select Yes, your file will be removed and a success message will be
  shown.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you select No, you file will not
  be remove and a message will be shown to confirm the file still exists.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Back to Main to return to the current file listing.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Hiding or Showing an Existing File</title><para>Hiding and
  showing a file will hide it from your site visitors or allow your vistors to
  view the file. Before hiding or showing a file, make sure you are positive
  you want to hide or show that particular file. Keep in mind, you can select
  multiple files from the file listing to hide or show. Follow these steps to
  hide or show your file(s):</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make sure you
  are logged in and have permission to use the File Manager.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Open
  your Control Panel.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the Site Content
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the File Manager
  module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find the file(s) you wish to hide
  or show in the file listing.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click the
  check box(es) next to the file(s) you wish to hide or show.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select
  the Hide or Show option from the drop down list of actions.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  Go.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The file listing will be refreshed with
  the file(s) you had selected hidden or visable.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>
</chapter>
