<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo><author><firstname>Adam</firstname><surname>Morton</surname>
  <email>adam@NOSPAM.tux.appstate.edu</email>
  </author></chapterinfo>

  <title>Form Generator</title>

  <section><title>Introduction</title><para>The <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis>
  is a module used to create online forms and collect data from your site
  visitors through these forms. Once data has been collected, Form Generator
  allows you to export the data into a tab delimited file. This allows you to
  import your data into a spreadsheet program such OpenOffice.org Calc or
  Microsoft Excel. Form Generator also offers some basic reporting features of
  it&#39;s own, but they are limited.</para><para>Some helpful things to
  remember when using the form generator:</para><orderedlist
  numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>The <emphasis>Main Menu</emphasis> is always
  shown across the top while administrating the Form Generator module. This
  menu allows you to perform key operations in certain areas of the Form
  Generator. Some of these operations include: New Form, List Forms, Settings,
  Report, and Archive.</para></listitem><listitem><para>When first entering the Form
  Generator the Main Menu will only show two options: <emphasis>New Form
  </emphasis> and <emphasis>List Forms</emphasis>. The Menu will expand
  it&#39;s options when a form has been selected from one of the lists of
  forms. Certain options are shown for saved forms and certain options shown
  for unsaved or unapproved forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>There are two parts to
  forms. <emphasis>Settings</emphasis> and <emphasis>Elements</emphasis>. A
  form&#39;s settings can be altered at any time in any form. They include
  settings like your instructions for the form, the submission message shown
  upon successful submission of a form, whether or not only registered users
  can view the form, and whether or not the form can be filled out multiple
  times by your users. A form&#39;s elements are the actual
  &#34;questions&#34; within your form. The elements are selected from a list
  of HTML elements like text field, text area, drop box, check box, radio
  button, and multi select. These elements can be used to ask and gather all
  sorts of information. A form&#39;s elements can only be edited when a form
  is in the unsaved state.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Under <emphasis>List Forms</emphasis>,
  three separate lists are shown. <emphasis>Saved Forms</emphasis> are forms
  that have been saved and may or may not contain data. That depends on
  whether or not you have the form available to your site visitors and whether
  or not those visitors have filled out the form. <emphasis>Unsaved Forms</emphasis>
  are forms that are being built but haven&#39;t been fully saved.
  <emphasis>Unapproved Forms</emphasis> are forms that were created by a user
  that is designated as needing approval of their forms before they are made
  available to the public. Once an unsaved or unapproved form is saved, it
  will move to the <emphasis>Saved Forms</emphasis> list.</para></listitem><listitem><para>When
  clicking on a form in a list, you will be viewing the form as a visitor to
  your site would view it. However, as an admin you will see the
  <emphasis>Main Menu</emphasis> at the top. From the menu you can select to
  perform various operations on the form you are viewing. You can always
  return to the form listing by clicking <emphasis>List Forms</emphasis>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Something
  to keep in mind when saving forms: Make sure you are positive the form is
  correct and ready to be viewed and filled out by your site visitors. Once a
  form is saved it will start collecting data. If you decide to edit the
  elements within that form, the data collected by the form must be
  <emphasis>cleared and archived </emphasis>. Hence, you reset the form when
  you edit it&#39;s elements. A good practice is to export the data from the
  form just before you edit it&#39;s elements. You can always edit a
  form&#39;s settings no matter which state it is in.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Creating a Form</title><para>It is a good idea to have your
  form planned out in advance before diving in and creating a form. In the
  plan, you should take into account the name of the form, the instructions
  for the form, the submission message for the form, the elements to be
  contained in the form and what HTML elements will be used to represent your
  form elements, and what type of users the form is geared towards (anonymous
  or registers visitors to your site). Once you have planned out the settings
  and elements for your form follow these steps to create your form:</para><orderedlist
  numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Make sure you are logged into an
  administrative account that has permissions to use the Form Generator.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>From your <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>, select
  the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis> tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and
  select the <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From
  the <emphasis>Main Menu</emphasis>, select <emphasis>New Form</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown the <emphasis>Settings</emphasis> for your new form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis></emphasis>Name, <emphasis>Instructions</emphasis>,
  <emphasis>Submission message</emphasis>, and other settings for your form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  your form falls into one of your site&#39;s <emphasis>categories</emphasis>,
  specify it as well.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click <emphasis>Save Settings</emphasis>
  to save your settings and begin adding elements to your form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will notice that the menu now has a <emphasis>Settings</emphasis> option and
  an <emphasis>Elements </emphasis> option. Selecting <emphasis>Settings</emphasis>
  will take you to editing the settings for your form and selecting
  <emphasis>Elements</emphasis> will take you to adding/editing of your
  form&#39;s elements.</para></listitem><listitem><para>To add an element to your form,
  select the element type you wish to add from the tool bar at the bottom and
  click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>See the section for
  adding the element you selected for more specific instructions for that
  element.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis>Continue adding elements</emphasis>
  until you have all your planned elements within your form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Take
  a <emphasis>final look</emphasis> at your form to make sure everything is in
  order and make changes where needed.</para></listitem><listitem><para>When you are sure
  your form is complete, click the <emphasis>Save Form</emphasis> button on
  the tool bar across the bottom to save your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Drop Box Element</title><para>Make sure you have
  planned out the format of your drop box before continuing. You should have
  in mind the label or question for the drop box, the number of options, the
  option text to be shown to the user, and the actual value of each option to
  be stored when it is selected.</para><para>Make sure you are editing the
  elements of the form you wish to add the drop box to. Select
  <emphasis>Dropbox</emphasis> from the drop down list of elements on your
  tool bar and click Add. Follow these steps to finish adding the element:</para><orderedlist
  numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for
  your element. The <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify
  this particular element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to
  auto-assign a unique name to your element, but if you would like a different
  name you can change it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain
  only alpha and numeric characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form
  you are editing.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis>
  for your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element.
  This text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Please
  select your age range:)</para></listitem><listitem><para>Enter the <emphasis>Number of
  Options</emphasis> to be used with the drop box or select a
  <emphasis>Predefined Option Set</emphasis> (see section Predefined Option
  Sets).</para></listitem><listitem><para>If this element is required to be filled out,
  check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis> check box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  <emphasis>Next</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you did not select a
  predefined option set, you will now need to fill out the information for
  each option in your drop box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For each option, enter the
  <emphasis>Text</emphasis> which will be the actual text shown to inside the
  drop box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For each option, enter the
  <emphasis>Value</emphasis> which will be the actual value stored if the
  corresponding option is selected. Optionally, if you the value you want to
  be stored is the same as the text entered for each option, you can select
  the <emphasis>Use option text as values</emphasis> check box at the bottom
  of the list of options. If that is selected, you do not need to fill out
  anything for the values of your options.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to
  have a certain option selected by default when the form is first shown to
  your site visitors, select the <emphasis>Default</emphasis> flag for the
  corresponding option.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to save the set of
  options you just created as a predefined option set, enter a name to save
  the option set as in the <emphasis>Save option set as</emphasis> field.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double
  check your option set and click <emphasis>Save Dropbox</emphasis> when
  finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The drop box will be saved and added to the
  end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Text Field Element</title><para>Make sure you have
  planned out the format of your text field before continuing. You should have
  in mind the label or question for the text field and whether or not the text
  field is required to be filled out.</para><para>Make sure you are editing
  the elements of the form you wish to add the text field to. Select
  <emphasis>Textfield </emphasis> from the drop down list of elements on your
  tool bar and click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>. Follow these steps to finish
  adding the element:</para><orderedlist numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for your element. The
  <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify this particular
  element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to auto-assign a unique
  name to your element, but if you would like a different name you can change
  it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain only alpha and numeric
  characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form you are editing.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis> for
  your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element. This
  text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Please enter
  your full name:)</para></listitem><listitem><para>Optionally, you can enter a
  <emphasis>Size</emphasis> and a <emphasis>Maxsize</emphasis> for your
  element. The size will be the actual size of the text field and will affect
  how many characters are shown at one time in the text field. The maximum
  size is the maximum number of characters you are willing to accept. A user
  may type in more than the maximum size allows, but the Form Generator will
  store only the number of characters specified with maxsize. If no size or
  maxsize is specified, Form Generator will fill in default values for you.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  this element is required to be filled out, check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis>
  check box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double check your input and click
  <emphasis>Save Textfield</emphasis> when finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The
  text field will be saved and added to the end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Text Area Element</title><para>Make sure you have
  planned out the format of your text area before continuing. You should have
  in mind the label or question for the text area and whether or not the text
  area is required to be filled out.</para><para>Make sure you are editing the
  elements of the form you wish to add the text area to. Select
  <emphasis>Textarea </emphasis> from the drop down list of elements on your
  tool bar and click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>. Follow these steps to finish
  adding the element:</para><orderedlist numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for your element. The
  <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify this particular
  element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to auto-assign a unique
  name to your element, but if you would like a different name you can change
  it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain only alpha and numeric
  characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form you are editing.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis> for
  your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element. This
  text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Please enter
  your full name:)</para></listitem><listitem><para>Optionally, you can enter the
  <emphasis>Rows</emphasis> and a <emphasis>Columns</emphasis> for your
  element. The rows will be the actual number of rows in the text area and
  will affect how many characters are shown per line. The columns are the
  actual number of columns in the text area and will affect how many lines of
  text are shown at a given time. If no rows or columns are specified, Form
  Generator will fill in default values for you.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If this
  element is required to be filled out, check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis>
  check box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double check your input and click
  <emphasis>Save Textarea</emphasis> when finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The
  text area will be saved and added to the end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Multiple Select Element</title><para>Make sure you
  have planned out the format of your multiselect before continuing. You
  should have in mind the label or question for the set, the number of
  options, the option text to be shown to the user, and the actual value of
  each option to be stored when it is selected.</para><para>Make sure you are
  editing the elements of the form you wish to add the multiple select to.
  Select <emphasis>Multiple Select</emphasis> from the drop down list of
  elements on your tool bar and click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>. Follow these
  steps to finish adding the element:</para><orderedlist numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for your element. The
  <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify this particular
  element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to auto-assign a unique
  name to your element, but if you would like a different name you can change
  it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain only alpha and numeric
  characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form you are editing.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis> for
  your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element. This
  text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Please select
  your age range:)</para></listitem><listitem><para>Enter the <emphasis>Number of Options</emphasis>
  to be used with the multiple select box or select a <emphasis>Predefined
  Option Set</emphasis> (see section: Predefined Option Sets).</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  this element is required to be filled out, check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis>
  check box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click <emphasis>Next</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  you did not select a predefined option set, you will now need to fill out
  the information for each option in your multiple select box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For
  each option, enter the <emphasis>Text</emphasis> which will be the actual
  text shown for options in the multiple select box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For
  each option, enter the <emphasis>Value</emphasis> which will be the actual
  value stored if the corresponding option is selected. Optionally, if you the
  value you want to be stored is the same as the text entered for each option,
  you can select the <emphasis>Use option text as values</emphasis> check box
  at the bottom of the list of options. If that is selected, you do not need
  to fill out anything for the values of your options.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  you wish to have a certain option selected by default when the form is first
  shown to your site visitors, select the <emphasis>Default</emphasis> flag
  for the corresponding option.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to save the
  set of options you just created as a predefined option set, enter a name to
  save the option set as in the <emphasis>Save option set as</emphasis> field.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double
  check your option set and click <emphasis>Save Multiselect</emphasis> when
  finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The multiple select box will be saved and
  added to the end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Radio Button Element</title><para>Make sure you
  have planned out the format of your set of radio buttons before continuing.
  You should have in mind the label or question for the set, the number of
  options, the option text to be shown to the user, and the actual value of
  each option to be stored when it is selected.</para><para>Make sure you are
  editing the elements of the form you wish to add the radio buttons to.
  Select <emphasis>Radio Button</emphasis> from the drop down list of elements
  on your tool bar and click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>. Follow these steps to
  finish adding the element:</para><orderedlist numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for your element. The
  <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify this particular
  element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to auto-assign a unique
  name to your element, but if you would like a different name you can change
  it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain only alpha and numeric
  characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form you are editing.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis> for
  your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element. This
  text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Please select
  your age range:)</para></listitem><listitem><para>Enter the <emphasis>Number of Options</emphasis>
  to be used with the radio button or select a <emphasis>Predefined Option Set</emphasis>
  (see section: Predefined Option Sets).</para></listitem><listitem><para>If this element
  is required to be filled out, check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis> check
  box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click <emphasis>Next</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If
  you did not select a predefined option set, you will now need to fill out
  the information for each option in your set of radio buttons.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For
  each option, enter the <emphasis>Text</emphasis> which will be the actual
  text shown next to the radio buttons.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For each option,
  enter the <emphasis>Value</emphasis> which will be the actual value stored
  if the corresponding option is selected. Optionally, if you the value you
  want to be stored is the same as the text entered for each option, you can
  select the <emphasis>Use option text as values</emphasis> check box at the
  bottom of the list of options. If that is selected, you do not need to fill
  out anything for the values of your options.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish
  to have a certain option selected by default when the form is first shown to
  your site visitors, select the <emphasis>Default</emphasis> flag for the
  corresponding option.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to save the set of
  options you just created as a predefined option set, enter a name to save
  the option set as in the <emphasis>Save option set as</emphasis> field.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double
  check your option set and click <emphasis>Save Radiobutton</emphasis> when
  finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The radio buttons will be saved and added to
  the end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Adding a Check Box Element</title><para>Make sure you have
  planned out the format of your check box before continuing. You should have
  in mind the label or question for the check box, the number of options, the
  option text to be shown to the user, and the actual value of each option to
  be stored when it is selected.</para><para>Make sure you are editing the
  elements of the form you wish to add the check box to. Select
  <emphasis>Checkbox </emphasis> from the drop down list of elements on your
  tool bar and click <emphasis>Add</emphasis>. Follow these steps to finish
  adding the element:</para><orderedlist numeration="arabic"><listitem><para>Fill
  out the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> for your element. The
  <emphasis>Name</emphasis> is used to uniquely identify this particular
  element within the form. Form Generator will attempt to auto-assign a unique
  name to your element, but if you would like a different name you can change
  it. The only restrictions are, the name must contain only alpha and numeric
  characters, NO spaces, and be unique within the form you are editing.
  </para></listitem><listitem><para>Fill out the <emphasis>Associated Text</emphasis> for
  your element. The associated text is the text shown with your element. This
  text can be a simple label, question, or instruction. (e.g.: Check if you
  wish to receive mail about upcoming events.) </para></listitem><listitem><para>Enter the
  <emphasis>Number of Options</emphasis> to be used with the check box or
  select a <emphasis>Predefined Option Set</emphasis> (see section: Predefined
  Option Sets).</para></listitem><listitem><para>If this element is required to be filled
  out, check the <emphasis>Required</emphasis> check box.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  <emphasis>Next</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you did not select a
  predefined option set, you will now need to fill out the information for
  each option in your set of check boxes.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For each option,
  enter the <emphasis>Text</emphasis> which will be the actual text shown next
  to the check boxes.</para></listitem><listitem><para>For each option, enter the
  <emphasis>Value</emphasis> which will be the actual value stored if the
  corresponding option is selected. Optionally, if you the value you want to
  be stored is the same as the text entered for each option, you can select
  the <emphasis>Use option text as values</emphasis> check box at the bottom
  of the list of options. If that is selected, you do not need to fill out
  anything for the values of your options.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to
  have a certain option selected by default when the form is first shown to
  your site visitors, select the <emphasis>Default</emphasis> flag for the
  corresponding option.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you wish to save the set of
  options you just created as a predefined option set, enter a name to save
  the option set as in the <emphasis>Save option set as</emphasis> field.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Double
  check your option set and click <emphasis>Save Checkbox</emphasis> when
  finished.</para></listitem><listitem><para>The check boxes will be saved and added to the
  end of your form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Editing, Removing, or Moving Elements</title><para>Editing,
  removing, and moving elements within a form are all similar operations. When
  editing a form&#39;s elements, the existing elements are shown with the
  element name and a drop box of options to the right of each element. To edit
  an element, select the <emphasis>Edit</emphasis> option from the drop box
  next to the appropriate element and click <emphasis>Go</emphasis>. You will
  be taken to a page exactly like the page shown when creating that particular
  element. Follow the instructions given for creating that particular element
  in their appropriate sections within this document.</para><para>To remove an
  element, select the <emphasis>Remove</emphasis> option from the drop box
  next to the appropriate element and click the <emphasis>Go</emphasis>
  button. You will be asked to confirm whether or not you wish to remove the
  element. Upon selecting <emphasis>Yes</emphasis> or <emphasis>No</emphasis>
  you will be taken back to editing your form.</para><para>To move an element,
  select the <emphasis>Move Up</emphasis> or <emphasis>Move Down</emphasis>
  option from the drop box next to the appropriate element and click the
  <emphasis>Go</emphasis> button. The element will be moved up or down in the
  form. If you element is at the beginning of the form and you select
  <emphasis>Move Up</emphasis>, the element will wrap to the end of the form
  and vice versa.</para></section>

  <section><title>Predefined Option Sets</title><para>Predefined option sets
  are sets of options that are used often when creating a form. Some examples
  might be Colors, Sex, Yes/No answers, etc. Predefined option sets are
  created when adding or editing a form element that can contain options.
  These elements are Dropbox, Radio Button, Multiple Select, and Checkbox. See
  step 10 for any of the mentioned elements for more details on actually
  saving predefined option sets. There is currently no method for
  administrating or deleting predefined option sets.</para></section>

  <section><title>Editing an Existing Form</title><para>First, you must be
  aware of the state of the form you wish to edit. If the form is saved, make
  sure you have exported your data before you attempt to edit it (see section
  <emphasis>Reporting on Form Data</emphasis>). Once you start editing the
  elements of a saved form, the form data collected is archived and cleared.
  Editing an unsaved or unapproved forms have no &#34;side-effects&#34; as
  they contain no data.</para><section><title>Editing an Unsaved or Unapproved
  Form</title><para>Make sure you have planned out the changes you wish to
  make to your form. In the plan you should take into account the elements you
  wish to remove, elements you wish to add, and settings you wish to change.
  If you are adding elements to the form, make sure you have carefully planned
  the settings needed for the elements as well as where those elements will
  appear in the form. Once you have your plan, follow these steps to edit your
  form:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make sure you are logged into an
  administrative account that has permissions to use the Form Generator.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From
  your <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>, select the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis>
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the
  <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown a list of your current forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  the form you wish to edit and click the linked <emphasis>Name</emphasis> of
  the form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>To edit the <emphasis>Settings</emphasis>
  for the form you selected, select the <emphasis>Settings</emphasis> link
  from the Main Menu.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Change any settings you
  had planned on changing and click the <emphasis>Save Settings</emphasis>
  button.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You will now be taken into editing
  the elements of the form you have selected.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Stick
  to your plan and remove or add elements in the same manner as when creating
  a form (see section <emphasis>Creating a Form</emphasis>).</para></listitem><listitem><para>When
  you have finished editing the elements within the form, take a moment to
  look over the form for typos or errors.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select
  <emphasis>Save Form</emphasis> from the tool bar when you are ready to save
  the form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section><section><title>Editing a
  Saved Form</title><para>If you are going to edit a saved form, make sure you
  have exported the form data before you continue (see section
  <emphasis>Reporting on Form Data</emphasis>).</para><para>Make sure you have
  planned out the changes you wish to make to your form. In the plan you
  should take into account the elements you wish to remove, elements you wish
  to add, and settings you wish to change. If you are adding elements to the
  form, make sure you have carefully planned the settings needed for the
  elements as well as where those elements will appear in the form. Once you
  have your plan, follow these steps to edit your form:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged into an administrative account that has permissions to
  use the Form Generator.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From your
  <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>, select the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis>
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the
  <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown a list of your current forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  the form you wish to edit and click the linked <emphasis>Name</emphasis> of
  the form.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select the <emphasis>Settings</emphasis>
  link from the Main Menu.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you are not
  editing the settings of the saved form, proceed to step 11, otherwise
  continue with step 8.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Change any settings
  you had planned on changing and click the <emphasis>Save Settings</emphasis>
  button.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You will be taken back to the form
  listing with the form&#39;s settings updated. If you still wish to edit the
  elements for the form, click the linked Name of the form you wish to edit.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select
  the Settings link from the Main Menu</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  the Edit Elements button at the bottom of the settings page.</para></listitem><listitem><para>At
  this point, Form Generator will want to archive your form and it&#39;s data.
  If you are sure you wish to continue to edit the form&#39;s elements,
  archive the form, and clear the form data, select the <emphasis>Confirm</emphasis>
  button. Otherwise, select <emphasis>Cancel</emphasis> and do not continue
  following these steps.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You will now be
  taken into editing the elements of the form you have selected. </para></listitem><listitem><para>Stick
  to your plan and remove or add elements in the same manner as when creating
  a form (see section <emphasis>Creating a Form</emphasis>).</para></listitem><listitem><para>When
  you have finished editing the elements within the form, take a moment to
  look over the form for typos or errors.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Select
  <emphasis>Save Form</emphasis> from the tool bar when you are ready to save
  the form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section></section>

  <section><title>Deleting a Form</title><para>First, make sure you know which
  form you wish to delete and that you are absolutely sure you wish to delete
  it permanently. If the form is a saved form, go ahead and export it&#39;s
  data before you delete it (see section <emphasis>Reporting on Form Data</emphasis>).
  When you have completed that, follow these steps to delete the form:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged into an administrative account that has permissions to
  use the Form Generator.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From your
  <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>, select the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis>
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the
  <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown a list of your current forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  the form you wish to delete and click the corresponding check box next to
  it&#39;s name.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Now select the
  <emphasis>Delete</emphasis> option from the drop box for the corresponding
  list (i.e.: Saved, Unsaved, or Unapproved).</para></listitem><listitem><para>Click
  <emphasis>Go</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You will now be
  asked to confirm the deletion of the form. Click <emphasis>Yes</emphasis> or
  <emphasis>No</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>If you selected
  <emphasis>Yes</emphasis>, your form will be deleted and you will be returned
  to the form listing. If you selected <emphasis>No</emphasis>, the form will
  not be deleted and you will be returned to the form listing.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Archiving a Form</title><para>Archiving a form is a good way
  to save a particular &#34;state&#34; of a form. Only saved forms can be
  archived since they are the only forms which could possibly contain data.
  When a form is archived, the form, it&#39;s elements, and all it&#39;s data
  are all saved in an archive file on the server. To retrieve an archived
  form, you need to contact your system administrator. Follow these steps to
  archive a form:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make sure you are logged
  into an administrative account that has permissions to use the Form
  Generator.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From your <emphasis>Control
  Panel</emphasis>, select the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis> tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  and select the <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown a list of your current forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  the form you wish to archive in the <emphasis>Saved Forms</emphasis> list
  and click it&#39;s <emphasis>Name</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>On
  the <emphasis>Main Menu</emphasis> you will see an <emphasis>Archive</emphasis>
  option. Click <emphasis>Archive</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Your
  form will be archived on the server and you will be taken to the
  <emphasis>Report</emphasis> view of the form.</para></listitem></orderedlist></section>

  <section><title>Reporting on Form Data</title><para>Reporting is only
  available for saved forms since they are the only forms that could possibly
  contain data. There are a couple of ways to report on data entered into a
  form. Form Generator has a built in method for browsing current entries in a
  form as well as a method for exporting this data into a tab delimited file
  that can be downloaded and imported into any spread sheet program (e.g.:
  OpenOffice.org Calc, Microsoft Excel, etc.).</para><para>First, to enter
  into reporting mode for a form, follow these steps:</para><orderedlist><listitem><para>Make
  sure you are logged into an administrative account that has permissions to
  use the Form Generator.</para></listitem><listitem><para>From your
  <emphasis>Control Panel</emphasis>, select the <emphasis>Site Content</emphasis>
  tab.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find and select the
  <emphasis>Form Generator</emphasis> module.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will be shown a list of your current forms.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Find
  the form you wish to report on and click it&#39;s <emphasis>Name</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  will now see a <emphasis>Report</emphasis> option available on the
  <emphasis>Main Menu</emphasis>. Click <emphasis>Report</emphasis>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>You
  are now in report mode for the form.</para></listitem></orderedlist><para>Some
  statistical data is calculated and displayed by Form Generator such as the
  number of complete and incomplete entries, the total number of entries, and
  the date and time of the last entry the form received. Shown below this
  information is a list of the actual entries received by the form. There are
  several options you have available for each entry. You can edit, delete,
  view, or print each entry.</para><para>When editing an entry, the form is
  loaded with the data populated, and you are allowed to change any value you
  wish. When viewing or printing an entry, just the raw data is shown and not
  the form in it&#39;s entirety. If you delete an entry, it is permanently
  removed from the form&#39;s data and can only be recovered through an
  archive if one exists. It is recommended you archive your form data before
  you edit or remove any of it&#39;s entries. This will ensure you have a
  backup copy in case of emergency.</para><para>To export all the data within
  the form, simply click the Export button. A archived &#34;.zip&#34; file
  will be created by the Form Generator and will be sent to you through your
  browser. Choose a suitable download location on your machine and save the
  file. To unzip the file you can use the unzip command in *nix or the winzip,
  winace, or winrar programs in a windows environment. A single file will be
  extracted that is a tab delimited file containing your form&#39;s data.
  Using a spread sheet program, import the file and then save it to a more
  workable format that is native to the program you&#39;re using (i.e.: *.sxc
  for OpenOffice.org Calc or *.xls for Microsoft Excel).</para></section>
</chapter>
