<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Steven</firstname>
      <surname>Levin</surname>
      <email>steven at tux dot appstate dot edu</email>
    </author>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Photo Albums</title>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>First navigate to the administrative side of the Photo Album module.
    It can be found under the Site Content Tab of your Control Panel. The link
    that says Photo Albums and has an icon of a camera next to it.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Click on the textual link or the icon to continue.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Listing Albums</title>

    <para>When you first enter the Photo Album you will see a listing of all
    the Photo Albums which are currently in the database. From this list you
    can go to view each individual album. In this album view you can see
    thumnail images of all the photos in the album. At the top of the page
    with this list are two links. The first link is for listing albums, it
    will to always bring you back to this list. The other link says New Album
    and will take you to the form you need to add a new photo album to the
    database.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Creating a New Album</title>

    <para>When creating a new Photo Album there are five fields to fill out
    but only one of them is actually required.</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The name of the album is the first field and the only required
        one. The name represents this album in the listing of all the photo
        albums and throughout phpWebSite.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The second field is a short; it allows you to add a short
        description of your album. This may be used in something like a search
        result.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The next option is to choose whether or not you want the album
        to be viewable by the public. Selecting visable makes it viewable by
        your users and the public alike. Selecting hidden keeps it out of the
        view of the public and only administrators with access can see the
        album.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Next you can select a category for the album to go in. This is
        very useful if you would like the album to show up as related data. If
        you do not understand categories and wish to find out more, please
        refer to the chapter about the FatCat Categorizer.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Finally you can add an extended description of your photo album.
        This is shown when listing all your albums so visitors can read about
        them. A wysiwyg html editor is provided for adding very basic html
        tags to the description.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Adding/Editing/Deleting Photos from an Album</title>

    <section>
      <title>Adding Photos</title>

      <para>When you are viewing an album for the first time and the album has
      no photos associated with it, you have two links to add a new photo. The
      first is under the message: No photos were found for this album; and it
      says Add a Photo. The second is a the top of the page next to the List
      Albums link and it says New Photo. The New Photo link will always be
      present when you are viewing an album. Both of these links take you to
      the same form to add a new photo.</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Two things are required when adding a new photo to the
          database. You must upload an image file and also provide a short
          description for that image. The short description is needed to make
          the html valid.</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Upload your image by clicking the browse button and
              selecting the file you want off of your computer.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>After that you can choose whether or not the photo is publicly
          viewable which is much like the activity for the album.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Finally you can add an extended description to the album which
          will be displayed when the individual photo is being viewed. A
          wysiwyg is provided here for your convenience.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Editing Photos</title>

      <para>Editing a photo allows you to update the information entered when
      adding that photo to the database. You can also remove the photo and add
      a new one if it better fits the album or description.</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>You can get to editing a photo by clicking on the edit link
          under its thumbnail in the main album view or by clicking the edit
          link when viewing an individual photo.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>To upload a new image you must first remove the old one by
          checking the box Remove Image under the photo and then clicking Save
          Photo. Then click the browse button and select a new image off your
          computer. Click Save Photo and you are done.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>You can also edit any of the textual data by just modifying it
          in the form and then clicking the Save Photo buttom. You will get a
          message saying the photo was successfully saved.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title> Deleting a Photo</title>

      <para>The are two points in the photoalbum where you can delete photos.
      One is in the main album view under each thumbnail is a delete link.
      Also when viewing a specific photo there is a delete link at the top of
      the page. After clicking the delete link it will take you to a Yes/No
      confirmation to make sure you want to delete the photo entirely from the
      album. The photo will also display below for confirmation. Click Yes to
      remove the photo and No to cancel the deletion process.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Album Settings</title>

    <para>The settings for an album are found under the main album view. Next
    to the List Albums and New Photo link is a settings link. These settings
    are the same information you filled out when creating a new album. It is
    helpful to be able to get to this so you can possibly update the
    description of your album or hide it from the public while you add new
    photos to it. Just click the Save Album submit button to save any changes
    you may have made.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Navigating Albums</title>

    <para>Navigating albums is easy. The are two navigation toolbars at the
    top and bottom of a main album view. The main album view is split up into
    pages. The limits on this toolbar control how many thumbnails to show per
    page. There are arrows (&#60;&#60; and &#62;&#62;) provided for moving
    back and forth from page to page. Also page links are there to help jump
    around from page to page. In order to view a photo all you must do is
    click on the thumbnail image. This will take you to a big view of that one
    specific image. Located at the top and bottom of the image will be
    &#60;&#60;Prev and Next&#62;&#62; links to page through each individual
    photo. At any time you can get back to the main album view by clicking the
    Back to Album link at the top of the page.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>