<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Darren</firstname>
      <surname>Greene</surname>
      <email>dg49379 at tux dot appstate dot edu</email>
    </author>

    <pubdate>2003-06-20</pubdate>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
        <date>2003-06-20</date>
        <authorinitials>DG</authorinitials>
        <revremark>First release</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>User documentation for the phpWebSite Poll module</para>
    </abstract>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Poll</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>
    The poll module is basically a one question survey to collect
    information about users preferences toward a
    particular subject.  So, what type of questions are meant for the
    Poll module?  The ideal type of questions are opinion based such
    as "How do you like the new site?" or "What is your favorite
    food?".  These questions don't have a right or wrong answer, but
    are different according to the individual taking the survey.  The
    Poll module allows you to show one question on the homepage of your
    site and then manages the voting and presentation of the results.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>After the poll module is installed, login in as an
    administrator and access Poll by going to the <emphasis>Control Panel ->
    Site Content -> Poll</emphasis>.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Add a New Poll</title>
 
    <para>To create your first poll follow the steps listed below:
      <orderedlist>
       <listitem>
         <para>
         Login in as an administrator with the permission to add a new
         poll. Access the Poll module.
         </para>
       </listitem>
       <listitem>
         <para>
         Click the link called <emphasis>'New'</emphasis> from the
         Poll administrative menu.  At this point you will be
         presented with a form to create a new poll.  The fields are
         explained below along with examples.
         <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
           <para><emphasis role="bold">Title</emphasis> - This is not
           the poll question, but instead a short title that is used as
           the block title.
           <example><title>Example</title><para>0.9.x</para></example>
           </para>
         </listitem>
         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Question</emphasis> - Put the survey
          poll question that you would like your users to vote on in
          this field.  
          <example><title>Example</title>
            <para>How do you like the new site?</para>
          </example>
          </para>
         </listitem>
       
         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Options</emphasis> - The options are
          the possible answers to the poll question.  The poll module
          defaults to showing only one field for an option, but you can
          have as many answers to your question as you would like by
          repeatedly clicking the button that says
          <emphasis>Add Option</emphasis>.
          </para>
         </listitem>

         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Users</emphasis> - Do you want users
          that are not logged into phpWebsite to be able to cast their
          vote on your poll?  If you choose <emphasis>'Yes'</emphasis>
          then only users that are logged in will be able to vote on
          the poll, and if you choose <emphasis>'No'</emphasis> then
          all users will be able to vote regardless of whether they
          are logged in or not.
          </para>
         </listitem>
 
         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Active</emphasis> - This option
          determines whether this poll will be placed on the homepage
          immediately after it is created.  Note that any poll that is
          currently active will be disabled and replaced by the new
          poll if set to active.  The old poll will not be deleted,
          just not active.  So, choose <emphasis>'Yes'</emphasis> to
          make this poll show on the homepage of your site or choose
          <emphasis>'No'</emphasis> to create the poll, but not make it
          visible at this time.
          </para>
         </listitem>

         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Allow Comments</emphasis> - Select
          <emphasis>'Yes'</emphasis> if you would like this poll to
          allow users to post comments regarding the poll, or else choose
          <emphasis>'No'</emphasis> to disable comments.  The user
          comments will appear on the <emphasis>'Poll
          Results'</emphasis> section. 
          </para>
         </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>
       Your new poll should now be successfully created after you click
       <emphasis>Submit</emphasis>
       </para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>   

   </para>
   </section>

   <section>
    <title>Editing and Deleting Polls</title>

    <para>
    If you wish to change or delete an existing Poll then follow the
    steps below:
    <orderedlist>
     <listitem>
      <para>
      To access the Poll module to update a poll you must be logged
      in as an administrator of Poll.
      </para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
       <para>Once you have access the Poll module, click the link 'Show Polls'
       from the Poll administrative menu.  You will see a listing of
       all the polls that have been created.  
       </para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para>Select the Poll you are interested in choose from one of
      the following options:
        <itemizedlist>
         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Edit</emphasis> - By choosing this
          option you will be presented with the same screen that was
          used to create the poll, but the form will be filled in with
          the text and options for this poll.  Note:  When editing a
          poll, if you choose to make a poll active, then any poll that
          is already active will be deactivated.  The poll module only
          allows one poll to be active at a time.
          </para>
         </listitem>
         <listitem>
          <para>
          <emphasis role="bold">Delete</emphasis> - This will remove
          the poll from the Poll module.
          </para>
         </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
       </para>
      </listitem>
      
     </orderedlist>
    </para>

   </section>

   <section>
    <title>View Poll Results</title>
    
    <para>
    You can only view the results of the currently active poll, which
    will be displayed on your site's homepage.  The Poll itself will
    show a count of the total users who have voted on the poll and how
    many users have submitted comments regarding the poll.  To view
    results of each of the answers to the survey questions, click the
    link <emphasis>'View Results'</emphasis> from the active poll on the
    homepage.  Each answer has associated with it a bar graph
    representing the number of votes the answer has received as a
    percentage of the other answers.
    </para>
   </section>

</chapter>