<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Approval List</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Some modules (e.g. Announcements, Calendar, Link Manager) allow
    users without permissions to submit content for approval by
    administrators. The Approval module is a central area for you to approve
    or disapprove user submissions.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>The Approval List module is in the Administration tab. Go to that
    tab under the control panel and click on the Approval link.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Entry List</title>

    <para>When a module needs something to get approved, it will appear on
    this list. Each module will be listed separately with its entries beneath.</para>

    <para>Some information will be provided in the <emphasis role="bold">Information</emphasis>
    section. You can receive more information by clicking on the <emphasis
    role="bold">View</emphasis> link.</para>

    <para>Once you have viewed the submission, you have three options per
    entry.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Yes</emphasis> - Choosing this radio
        button means you wish to accept the entry and write it permanently to
        the system.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">No</emphasis> - Choosing this radio button
        means you do not want to approve this entry and want it removed from
        the system.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Ignore</emphasis> - Choosing this radio
        button (which by default is selected) will skip over that entry for a
        later decision.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>Once you have picked your choices, click the <emphasis role="bold">Go</emphasis>
    button at the bottom of this list. That is all there is to it.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <para>Check your Approvals List about once a day or more depending upon
    your site&#39;s traffic.</para>

    <para>If you have any questions or comments about this document, please
    contact me at matt at tux dot appstate dot edu.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
