<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Matthew</firstname>

      <surname>McNaney</surname>
    </author>

    <address>matt at tux dot appstate dot edu</address>

    <pubdate>2003-06-12</pubdate>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>

        <date>2003-06-12</date>

        <authorinitials>MM</authorinitials>

        <revremark>First release</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>This is user documentation for the FatCat Categorizer module for
      phpWebSite.</para>
    </abstract>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>FatCat Categorizer</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Most content modules in phpWebSite share a common need: to
    categorize its data. Instead of having each module track categorizes
    independently, FatCat manages it for them all. Centralized categories
    allows greater interactivity and ordering of data.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>Before we begin creating categories, we need to decide the structure
    of our tree. The amount of time you spend upfront determining how your
    category tree will branch will save you ten times that amount of time in
    the future.</para>

    <para>First ask yourself, what is the purpose of my site? Let&#39;s say I
    am making a site about cooking. I may decide my site&#39;s purpose is to
    post recipes. So, I might make the first two categories
    <emphasis><emphasis role="bold">Recipes</emphasis></emphasis> and
    <emphasis><emphasis role="bold">Advice</emphasis></emphasis>. Then I would
    determine how to organize my recipes. I decide to make three categories
    under Recipes: <emphasis role="bold">Desserts</emphasis>, <emphasis
    role="bold">Main Course</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">Appetizers</emphasis>.
    Under Advice, I would make the categories <emphasis role="bold">Dietetic</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="bold">Preparation</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">Appliances</emphasis>,
    and <emphasis role="bold">Utensils</emphasis>. That should be enough to
    get started. I may decide to add more categories later. For example, under
    Preparation I may have the categories <emphasis role="bold">Poultry</emphasis>,
    <emphasis role="bold">Vegetables</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">Beef</emphasis>
    because I feel each of those deserves a separate area of preparation. Or
    if I think there won&#39;t be enough information under Poultry and Beef, I
    may combine them under one category: <emphasis role="bold">Meat</emphasis>.
    You aren&#39;t chained to the choices you make for categories but it will
    save you time if you plan beforehand.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Categories</title>

    <para>Now that I know what categories I need, I can start making them. We
    know the top two categories (Recipes and Advice), so we will want to make
    those first.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Creating Categories</title>

      <para>First go into your control panel and click on the Site Content
      tab. Next click on the FatCat Categorizer option. Once there you should
      see a drop down box with the words <emphasis role="bold">&#60;Top
      Level&#62;</emphasis>. Next to that is a button labeled <emphasis
      role="bold">Create Category</emphasis>. Since we are first making our
      top level categories, this is a good selection. Go ahead and click the
      aforementioned button. You will now come to the Create Category form.
      Let&#39;s go through the elements of the form.
      <itemizedlist><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Parent</emphasis> -
      This controls the parent of the category I am creating. This echoes my
      selection from the previous page. Since I want Recipes to be at the top
      of my category tree I will leave this at &#60;Top Level&#62;.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Title</emphasis> - Fairly self-explanatory. I will just type
      &#34;Recipes&#34; here.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Description</emphasis> - Although not required, it is a good
      idea to explain the purpose of a category. Type the description of the
      category here (e.g. &#34;Recipes are your culinary blueprints to great
      food!&#34;).</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Template</emphasis>
      -The template controls the layout of the View Category page. Just leave
      this to default.tpl.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Image and Icon</emphasis> - You may to upload an image for
      you category. Make sure to read the Images and Icons information below (<link
      linkend="images_and_icons">Section 4</link>)</para></listitem></itemizedlist>When
      I have finished entering the information on my Recipes category, I will
      click the Create Category button. My first category is complete!</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Other Categories</title>

      <para>Once you create your first category you should be able to start
      developing your &#34;tree&#34;.</para>

      <para>Earlier we decided to create categories named Desserts, Main
      Course, and Appetizers. Choosing Recipes instead of &#60;Top Level&#62;
      from the drop box allows me to create these categories under Recipes. I
      can also choose a parent from the drop down box on the creation screen.</para>

      <simplelist type="vert">
        <member>Recipes</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Desserts</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Main Course</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Appetizers</member>
      </simplelist>

      <para>Once I pick Recipes as the parent, I would just create these other
      categories as I did their parent. If you are following along, you should
      start to see more options in your drop down box. You would see something
      like the following list:</para>

      <simplelist type="vert">
        <member>Recipes</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Desserts</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Desserts &#62; Cakes</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Desserts &#62; Pies</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Main Course</member>

        <member>Recipes &#62; Appetizers</member>
      </simplelist>

      <para>The greater than sign (&#62;) indicates that Desserts, Main Course
      and Appetizers are under the Recipes category. If Desserts had
      categories beneath it, the list might look something like the following:</para>

      <para>The list can continue like this forever, but don&#39;t try to get
      there. Keep your list orderly. Three to four categories should be
      sufficient. If biologists can classify all life with only seven category
      levels, you should be able to make do with five.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Editing Categories</title>

      <para>Should you need to edit a category, just select it from the drop
      down box on the administration page and click the Edit Category button.
      You will be taken to a page quite similar to the creation page. Edit
      your changes and click the Update Category button.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Removing Categories</title>

      <para>If you decide you want to remove a category from the system, make
      absolutely sure you have moved any subcategories to another parent. All
      information associated to the category will be removed permanently. When
      you are certain you want to remove this category, choose it from the
      drop down box on the administration page and click the Delete Category
      button.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="images_and_icons">
    <title>Images and Icons</title>

    <para>When creating or editing categories, you may decide you want to add
    a little more flair to them with graphics. FatCat allows you to upload
    images and icons to each category.</para>

    <para>Size is the biggest difference between an image and an icon. Images
    are much larger than icons. The other difference is where they show up.
    Icons are commonly accompany information under that category. Images are
    usually only seen when some if reading information about the category
    itself.</para>

    <para>Before we get started, let&#39;s lay down the rules for images and
    icons.<orderedlist><listitem><para>Images and icons should be of the gif,
    jpeg (or jpg as it is more commonly spelled), or png format. You can tell
    what format your graphic is by looking at the file extension (i.e. the
    last three letters of filename). Any other image types (e.g. bmp, wmp, psd
    etc.) won&#39;t be allowed.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Icons must be
    even smaller: 50 pixels wide by 50 pixels high or less.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Images
    should be around 200 pixels wide by 200 pixels high. Anything larger than
    that tends to gobble up space and detract from the description of the
    category.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Both icons and images should
    have a resolution of 72 dots per inch (or dpi). Remember, monitors
    don&#39;t need high resolution to show a clear picture. Anything over
    72dpi is overkill and makes the image file bloated. Digital cameras
    usually store pictures at 300dpi to 1200dpi so be careful.</para></listitem></orderedlist>To
    upload an image, click the <emphasis role="bold">Browse</emphasis> button.
    Go to the directory that contains your image file and select it by double
    clicking or clicking OK. The directory path to your image should now
    appear in the text box next to the Browse button. Now if you create or
    update your category, the image will accompany the title and description
    on the view page.</para>

    <para>You can upload an icon the same way. Click <emphasis role="bold">Browse</emphasis>,
    choose your icon, and save the category.</para>

    <para>After uploading at least one image or icon to the system, you will
    see a drop down box with that graphics file name selected. If you decide
    you do not want to use a graphic for the category you can choose <emphasis
    role="bold">&#60;None&#62;</emphasis> in the drop down box. If you later
    prefer to use a different graphic entirely, you can select it from the
    drop down box as well.</para>

    <para>Finally if you never want to see a graphic again, select the file
    name and click the <emphasis role="bold">Remove Image</emphasis> or
    <emphasis role="bold">Remove Icon</emphasis> button.</para>

    <para>One other feature you can take advantage of on this page is
    <emphasis role="bold">thumbnails</emphasis>. These are small versions of
    the currently selected image. Once created, they can be used as icons.
    Creating them is easy, either Browse to the image you want to use or
    select on from the image drop down box and then click the <emphasis
    role="bold">Create Icon</emphasis> from Image button. Your new icon will
    then be set!</para>

    <para>A few rules about thumbnail icons. First, not all images lend
    themselves well to icons. A landscape for example would be unrecognizable
    as an icon. An image of a object or a portrait would lend itself well to
    an icon. Experiment with them. Second, you can only make thumbnails from
    jpg or png image files. Sorry, but gif files are copyrighted material and
    you have to pay to alter the format.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Now What?</title>

    <para>So how are these categories used? Most of the content modules that
    come with phpWebSite tap in to FatCat.</para>

    <para>When you create an event, announcement, or a page there is a
    multiple select list to choose the category (or categories) to which you
    want that item associated. To select the category or categories associated
    to your item, highlight them by clicking each one. Hold down the CTRL key
    on your keyboard while left clicking to highlight more than one at a time.
    When you save your item, it will be indexed to the categories you have
    selected.</para>

    <para>Categorization comes in handy when another item shares that
    category. Let&#39;s say I have a pecan pie recipe (my favorite). I go
    under PageMaster and create the recipe page for it. I decide to assign the
    page to the category Recipes &#62; Desserts &#62; Pies.</para>

    <para>Later I find out there is going to be a pecan pie bake-off where I
    live. So I post an announcement with the same category. Since I may post a
    lot of announcements, I decide to post the event to my calendar.</para>

    <para>Now when the users come to my site they may see the announcement
    about the bake off. When they read it, a different box, the <emphasis
    role="bold">What&#39;s Related</emphasis> box, will appear showing them
    the other items that are related to this announcement, namely the calendar
    event and the recipe page. They can then click the event or the recipe
    page to get more information. As you add more content and use FatCat to
    categorize them, the easier and more interactive your site becomes.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Sticky Items</title>

    <para>Sometimes there is something that is so important, you want to make
    sure it is seen whenever something in the same category is viewed. To do
    so, you can just check the Sticky check box under the category listing.
    Although there is a limit on how many related items can appear, Sticky
    items will ALWAYS appear.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Back to the Admin</title>

    <para>You should now be familiar with creating, editing, and using
    categories in FatCat. You should be aware of two more options on the
    administration screen.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Default Icon</title>

      <para>Some modules, like Announcements, make extensive use of the
      category icons. Sometimes you may want to supply a filler icon for a
      category. The Default Icon option will assist you. Just pick an icon you
      have on your computer or use one you have already uploaded. See <link
      linkend="images_and_icons">Images and Icons</link> above to see how to
      choose an icon.</para>

      <para>Once you have selected your Default Icon, this picture will
      represent any category currently lacking an icon.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>What&#39;s Related Limit</title>

      <para>Earlier, you learned about the What&#39;s Related box. Pick a
      number from this drop down box to determine the maximum amount of
      related elements to display per module. Remember that Sticky items will
      always appear, ignoring the limit number.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <para>Hopefully you should now be able to use categories to their fullest.
    The more you use them, the more information you give your users. If you
    have any questions about this documentation, please contact me at matt at
    tux dot appstate dot edu.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
