<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Introductory Concepts</title>

  <section>
    <title>How phpWebSite Works</title>

    <para>In order to better understand how to use phpWebSite to create a web
    site, let&#39;s take a look at a typical site. By identifying the various
    elements that make up your site from a visitor&#39;s perspective, the
    administrative interface will make more sense once you begin using the
    tools.</para>

    <para>The page pictured below represents a fairly typical phpWebSite
    generated web page - no doubt you have seen something like it many times
    when surfing the web. </para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/homepage.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>A menu is in the upper left-hand corner, There is some general
    information site, front and center where we would expect it. Several
    important notices are on the site and some information is highlighted in a
    column on the far right of the page.</para>

    <para>Using traditional tools like Dreamweaver or Frontpage, our approach
    to building a page like this would be to start placing graphics, links,
    and text on a &#34;blank&#34; page much like we would create a print
    document. After a bit of work, we could reproduce the page above. And we
    would have produced just that - a single, solitary page.</para>

    <para>Now let&#39;s pause a moment and look at the main administrative
    page for phpWebSite. A few things stand out. We are looking at a web page
    in a browser, and the layout area common to many web page generation tools
    is nowhere to be found.</para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/modules.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>Instead we have a collection of icons and links. These represent the
    various modules that allow you to provide and manage content for your
    site. Unlike single-page generation tools, phpWebSite serves as a
    framework that dynamically organizes your content. Each page you view on
    your site is the work of many modules providing information that the
    phpWebSite engine puts together into the web page viewed by the site
    visitor. Let&#39;s look at that original web page again, this time showing
    the modules that are working together to build the page:</para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/homepage_module_use.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>What we see now is that phpWebSite has gathered up and presented the
    information on the site based on the module used to provide it. Different
    modules handle different types of information. One of the keys to using
    phpWebSite successfully is using the right module for the right
    information. In the pages that follow, each module is covered in detail.
    The important thing to note at this point is that we manage our site by
    managing our content. This is why phpWebSite is frequently referred to as
    a &#34;Content Management System&#34;.</para>

    <para>You may be wondering how to control to control the layout of a page.
    You should note that the layout of the example given is just one of the
    many possible. Layout is controlled via the layout module in combination
    with HTML templates, both of which are covered later. Rest assured that
    pretty much any look and feel can be achieved - here we are just
    interested in &#39;information elements&#39; that comprise a site.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Making a New Block - a Mini Tutorial</title>

    <para>So, how do we enter our content using a particular module? One of
    the nice things about phpWebSite is that the module interfaces are all
    very consistent. Content is entered via easy to use web forms. As an
    introduction, let&#39;s make a new Block using Block Maker.</para>

    <para>Log on to your phpWebSite installation using the User-name and
    Password you set during installation, or that your web administrator has
    provided you. Appalachian State University users should use the
    departmental training area that has been installed. If you don&#39;t have
    phpWebSite installed, you can use the phpWebSite public demo at <ulink
    url="http://phpwebsite.appstate.edu/demo/0.9.x/">
    http://phpwebsite.appstate.edu/demo/0.9.x/</ulink></para>

    <para>Once logged in, click on the &#34;Control Panel&#34; link in your
    administrative menu. This will open the main main administrative menu.
    Click the &#34;Site Content&#34; tab. You should see the main site content
    module group. Depending on your installation, you may not have all the
    modules that are shown here, but in all likelihood, Block Maker is
    installed, as it a simple and extremely useful module!</para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/open_modules.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>Click the icon or the &#34;Block Maker&#34; Link to open the Block
    Maker interface. Choose &#34;Create a New Block&#34; from the Block Menu.
    Now we only need to enter some content for our new block. Recall that
    blocks on our page are small and used for small amounts of text, but have
    the advantage of being in a prime location on your site. So let&#39;s give
    our new block a Title and some light text. Don&#39;t worry about the block
    footer or the Theme Variable - we will cover those in detail later. Select
    &#34;Home&#34; from the &#34;Allow View&#34; select list (this tells
    phpWebSite to only display this block on the home page). You should have
    something like this:</para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/block_content.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>Now just just click &#34;Create Block&#34; and your and block has
    been created. You will notice you are now at a screen that lists all of
    your blocks. You should also note that the block you just made has a
    button next to it that says &#34;Activate&#34;</para>

    <screenshot>
      <graphic fileref="images/activate_block.png" />
    </screenshot>

    <para>You block will not be displayed until you choose to have it
    displayed. Clicking &#34;Activate&#34; will do this. You can now check the
    home page by clicking Home on the Main Menu, and you should see your new
    block.</para>

    <para>Creating a Block is very simple, but encapsulates the basic content
    creation process for all modules. Text is supplied via simple web forms,
    options for display are point and click affairs, and content can be made
    active when it is ready to be &#34;published&#34;. You now are ready to
    start exploring more modules.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
