<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Welcome</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>phpWebSite is an extremely powerful web site management tool.
    Publishing information to the web using phpWebSite is easy, intuitive, and
    does not require technical skills. Keeping web site information current is
    simple using browser-based management. phpWebSite lets the user focus on
    what is important - the content, not the technology.</para>

    <para>The systems administrator will find that maintenance of even a very
    large number of sites is easy using a wide range of powerful tools. The
    look and feel of an entire site can be changed in a matter of seconds with
    only a few mouse clicks, and a wide variety of software modules allow for
    easy site customization without the need for unwanted or unused features.</para>

    <para>For the PHP developer, phpWebSite provides an ideal platform for
    rapidly developing sophisticated web-based applications. phpWebSite has a
    rich API - a full complement of powerful functions that ease development
    considerably. The goal of phpWebSite is to provide a flexible solution by
    following the premise that a module should do one thing very well and that
    all the modules should work together.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Intended Audience</title>

    <para>This manual is presented in three distinct volumes. The first volume
    is for the typical day to day user of the software. This volume contains
    information on how to use most of the core modules which comprise a
    minimal installation, as well as information on how to use the many
    modules that can be optionally installed. The instructions presented in
    this volume assume little or no technical expertise - any user familiar
    with a web browser should be at home here. This volume assumes you have a
    working copy of phpWebSite installed and access to the modules covered.</para>

    <para>The second volume contains information regarding how to install,
    upgrade, and maintain phpWebSite. The reader is assumed to be familiar
    with basic systems administration skills. A solid understanding of your
    operating system, database and web server is required. A working knowledge
    of PHP is helpful, but not required.</para>

    <para>The third volume is for the developer who wishes to write modules
    for phpWebSite. It fully discusses the phpWebSite API and covers the
    technical inner-workings of phpWebSite. A firm understanding of PHP and
    object oriented programing is required. </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Who Publishes phpWebSite?</title>

    <para>phpWebSite is free, open source software written and maintained by
    the Web Technology Group at Appalachian State University in Boone, NC,
    USA. The Web Technology group is comprised of both University staff and
    upper level and graduate Computer Science students who provide web based
    software solutions for the Student Development Division of Appalachian
    State. phpWebSite was originally developed as a solution for managing web
    site content at the University and was released as open source software in
    an effort to share our work in a cooperative spirit. Those involved at the
    beginning of the project never would have guessed that phpWebSite would
    grow to become the immensely popular application it is today.</para>

    <para>The Web Technology group owes sincere thanks to the many external
    developers who took notice of the phpWebSite project and have volunteered
    an enormous amount of time and effort to the project. Our thanks also to
    the many who have chosen to use phpWebSite, your bug reports and good
    ideas for features are extremely valuable. Ultimately, phpWebSite is the
    work of a diverse community of many people across the globe - a tribute to
    the power of shared ideas within the commons.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>