<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <chapterinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Matthew</firstname>

      <surname>McNaney</surname>
    </author>

    <address>matt at tux dot appstate dot edu</address>

    <pubdate>2003-06-12</pubdate>

    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>

        <date>2003-06-12</date>

        <authorinitials>MM</authorinitials>

        <revremark>First release</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>

    <abstract>
      <para>Description of document</para>
    </abstract>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Layout Admin</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>The Layout module controls the appearence of your web site. The
    colors, shape, and layout of the page display are based on the settings in
    Layout. This document will help you get the most out the module.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <para>Before jumping into the module, there are a few terms you need to be
    familiar with.</para>

    <para>Themes are what control the design of the site. Layout pipes the
    content you enter into boxes (see below) that are placed into the theme.
    Therefore, you can alter the way your page looks without having to worry
    about the content of your site.</para>

    <para>Boxes are what make up the themes. Each portion of content is
    seperated into these boxes, ordered, then placed on the theme.</para>

    <para>Now that you know these terms, let get into the module itself.
    Layout is an administrative module, so click on the Administrative tab in
    your control panel. Click on Layout Admin to get into the module. You will
    be taken to a page with two sections: the panel and the settings.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Layout Settings</title>

    <para>This section alters some key information and usability for your
    site. Fortunately, you probably won&#39;t have to alter the data here very
    often.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Change Page Title</title>

      <para>If you have your browser open, look at the very top of the browser
      window. You should see something like the following:
      <emphasis>Title of Website - Name of Browser</emphasis>. phpWebSite
      ships with the page title set to, what else, phpWebSite. You should
      change that. Determine the name of your site and type it in to the text
      field next to the <emphasis role="bold">Change Page Title</emphasis>
      button.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Edit Meta Tags</title>

      <para>The Internet has several search engines. Some of the ones you
      probably heard of are Google, Yahoo, Altavista, and Ask Jeeves. Each of
      the engines wants a quick way to get information about your site. Here
      is where meta tags come in. Choose one of the meta tags you wish to edit
      and click the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Metatags</emphasis> button.<itemizedlist><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Keywords</emphasis> - Marvelous. Informative. Great. These
      are words that may describe your web site. However, what you want to put
      here are words that describe the content of your site, not how you feel
      about it. Enter words you believe someone may type into a search engine
      and see your site listed. If you have a web site about board games, you
      could have a list like this:<blockquote><para>board games, monopoly,
      sorry, Milton Bradley, twister, Risk </para></blockquote></para><para>Put
      in as many words as you can think of that relate to what your site
      addresses. Do not put words that don&#39;t relate to your site just to
      get lost web surfers. It irritates people. </para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Description</emphasis> - Here you want to have a short (read
      that again: short) description of your site. Summarize all the great
      things your site provides within about 260 characters. Some search
      engines display this information when a match to your site is found.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Robots</emphasis> - When a search engine comes to your page,
      it will (sometimes) ask permission before it records it. Robots are your
      traffic guards. They tell the search engine whether to record this page
      (or <emphasis role="bold">index</emphasis>) or not and whether it can
      <emphasis role="bold">follow</emphasis> links on your page or not. You
      have four options:</para><itemizedlist><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">all</emphasis> - This tells the engine that they may index
      your site and continue down all the links on your page.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">none</emphasis> - The engine is told to leave you alone:
      don&#39;t index the site and don&#39;t follow any links. You may prefer
      this if you are running a private site.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">index, nofollow</emphasis> - The engine can index the page
      but shouldn&#39;t follow any links.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">noindex, follow</emphasis> - The engine should not index the
      page, but may follow your links.<note><para>This option is currently
      useless. Currently Layout reports these robots on every page. The engine
      goes down your link path but is not allowed to index any of the
      resultant pages. This will change in 0.9.3.</para></note></para></listitem></itemizedlist></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Author</emphasis> - This is your name or the name of the
      main content person. Not really required.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Owner</emphasis> - This is usually the email address of the
      person responsible for the site. Beware filling this out however as
      there are evil, nasty, horrible, people who steal these addresses to
      send you their useless spam email (not that I am bitter). If you wish to
      fill it out, consider entering your email address in a form that is hard
      to parse by the spam degenerates. For example, I might use: matt at
      hotmail dot com instead of matt@hotmail.com.</para></listitem><listitem><para><emphasis
      role="bold">Content Type</emphasis> - This reports the character sets
      your site is using. Just let this sit at ISO-8859-1 unless you know it
      should be otherwise.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Reinitialize Default Theme</title>

      <para>You can try clicking on this button if your boxes have become
      scrambled. It will try to recreate the default layout for the theme you
      are currently using. Be careful as some modules add boxes outside of
      their defaults. If that is the case you might have to go to that module
      and update the data to have it remake the box.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Refresh Boxes</title>

      <para>Click this button to purge the database of old box files that
      aren&#39;t supported anymore. This should be run if you remove a theme
      from your server directory.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>User can change theme</title>

      <para>If you have several themes installed on your site, you may want to
      give the users the ability to change which one they see. This can come
      in handy, for example, if you have a color blind or text only theme. If
      you change this to off, users won&#39;t be able to change the theme.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Layout Panel</title>

    <para>After going into the Layout module, you will see a Layout panel at
    the top of the page. This panel follows you around until you close it. The
    Layout panel lets you control the type and position of the boxes in your
    theme. It also lets you control which theme your site uses.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Move Boxes</title>

      <para>If you don&#39;t like the position of a box on your page, you can
      change it by click the <emphasis role="bold">On</emphasis> link. After
      you do this, you will see a series of arrows on the top left corner and
      bottom right corner of each box. These are what you will click to move
      the boxes.</para>

      <para>Before trying this however, lets talk about the structure of your
      page. Theme layouts are arranged in quadrants. The quadrants are
      (usually) in a ticktacktoe pattern. Each quadrant is a theme variable.</para>

      <para>Now if you look next to the arrows you will see a series of
      numbers separated with colons, like so: 2:1:2. The first number in our
      code is the column. The second number is the row. The third number is
      the queue order.</para>

      <para>We will get to the third number in a moment, but first lets look
      at the first two numbers. Here are out quadrant codes with the default
      theme variables in parenthesises:<table><title>Layout example</title><tgroup
      cols="3"><tbody><row><entry>1:1 (left_col_top)</entry><entry>2:1 (top)</entry><entry>3:1
      (right_col_top)</entry></row><row><entry>1:2 (left_col_mid)</entry><entry>2:2
      (body)</entry><entry>3:2 (right_col_mid)</entry></row><row><entry>1:3
      (left_col_bottom)</entry><entry>2:3 (bottom)</entry><entry>3:3
      (right_col_bottom)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></para>

      <para>So if we look at our example above (2:1:2) we can see that a box
      with this number is in the second column, first row.</para>

      <para>Now lets look at the third number. That is the box queue. Each
      quadrant can hold several boxes. These boxes need to be ordered as well.
      So using the code, we would know that the box is in the second (2) queue
      position. This means there is one box above the 2:1:2 box. This does not
      mean you will always see that box however. The visibility of a box
      depends upon what module is running, what page is being visited and
      other factors.</para>

      <para>Now back to box moving. Let&#39;s look at the top left series of
      arrows. The first one is a single up arrow. If I click it, that box will
      move up in the queue. Our 2:1:2 box would then be 2:1:1. Since our box
      would be at the top the queue, clicking the single arrow again would
      send it to the next row. Since 2:1:1 is the top row, this would actually
      wrap the box to the bottom row. So 2:1:1 would now be 2:3:5. Why is the
      last number five? Because there are already four other boxes in that
      quadrant. The single down arrow in the lower right corner of the box
      does exactly the opposite.</para>

      <para>The next arrow at the top left is a single arrow pointing to the
      left. This sends the box to the left. So our 2:3:5 box would then be in
      quadrant 1:3:7. Anytime a box is sent to a new quadrant, it is placed at
      the end of the box queue. The single right arrow in the lower right
      corner moves the box to the right.</para>

      <para>Finally you will notice the double arrow pointing up or down.
      Clicking this tells Layout to send the box to the front or bottom of the
      queue line. So if our box is in the 1:3:7 position and I click the
      double up arrow, it will be transferred to the 1:3:1 position. Clicking
      the double down arrow would send it where? That is correct! To the 1:1:5
      position. Why? Because the 1:3:7 is the end of the queue. Remember when
      we moved it from the right? Since it is at the end of the queue it would
      wrap from the bottom back to the top quadrant. Since it is in a new
      quadrant, it is put at the bottom of the queue.</para>

      <para>Confused yet? It will make more sense when you start clicking on
      the arrows. Click on the <emphasis role="bold">Off</emphasis> link when
      you are done.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Change Box Style</title>

      <para>Just as there are many boxes that make up a theme, there can also
      be several different box styles included with it. After you click the
      <emphasis role="bold">On</emphasis> link, a drop down box will appear
      under each box. Pick the box style you wish to use and click set. The
      box will then change to the new style. Click the <emphasis role="bold">Off</emphasis>
      link when you are finished.<note><para>This is why the panel follows you
      around until it is closed. You might need to maneuver to a specific page
      before you can change a box style or position.</para></note></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Set Default Theme</title>

      <para>Your default theme is what users see when they first come to the
      site. If you allow users to pick their own theme, that user (and only
      that user) will see their theme when they log in. You can change your
      default theme by choosing one from the drop down menu and clicking the
      button.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Settings and Close Panel</title>

      <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Settings</emphasis> link takes you back
      to the Layout administration screen. Click on the <emphasis role="bold">Close
      Panel</emphasis> button when you are finished using Layout.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <para>Hopefully you now know how to change the look of your site without
    much hassle. If you have any questions about the Layout module, please
    visit us at Sourceforge. If you have any questions or comments about this
    document, please direct them to matt at tux dot appstate dot edu.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
